- [ Banging On Door ]- [ Person Snorts ]
-[敲門聲]-[鼻息聲]
[ Person Groans ]
[抱怨聲]
[ Banging Continues ]
[敲門聲繼續]
[ Exhales ]Oh, fuck.
靠.
- [ Banging Continues ]- [ Coughs, Clears Throat ]
-[敲門聲繼續]-[咳嗽，清喉嚨]
- Uh, yeah?- Miles, can you move your car, please?
-怎麼了？-Miles，你能不能挪一下你的車，拜託？
- Why?- Because the roofers gotta get the truck in.
-為什麼？-因為修屋頂工人的卡車要進來。
- You didn't park too good. Okay?- Yeah. All right.
-你車停的不太對。好麼？-好。行。
Hold on.
等一下。
Sorry. Sorry, gentlemen.
抱歉，抱歉，先生們。
[ Clears Throat ]Sorry.
對不起。
[ Engine Starts ]
[引擎發動]
[ Panicked Panting ]
[氣喘吁吁聲]
Oh, fuck me!
哦，靠！
I know I saidI would be there by noon...
我知道我說過會在中午前到那兒
but, uh, there's all of this workgoing on at my building...
但是我的樓在翻修有一大堆的事
and it's just a total nightmare.
簡直就是場噩夢
I had a bunch of stuffI had to deal with this morning...
我有些事今天早上必須處理
but I'm on my way.
不過，我已經上路了。
I'm out the door right now.
我現在就出門了。
[ Water Running ]
[流水聲]
- [ Miles ] Hi, Simon.- [ Simon ] Hey, Miles.
嗨，Simon.嗨，Miles.
- Triple espresso, please?- For here?
- 三倍濃縮咖啡- 在這裡喝麼？
Uh, no, actually.I'm running late. Make it to go.
呃，不。我已經晚了，給我打包吧。
And give me a New York Timesand a spinach croissant.
再給我一份紐約時報和一個菠菜牛角麵包。
Thank you.
謝謝。
[ Doorbell Rings ]
[門鈴響]
- Ah!- Well, hello!
- 啊！- 嗯，你好。
- Hello, Mrs. Erganian. How are you?- Come on in.
- 你好，Erganian夫人。最近好麼？- 進來吧。
- Thank you. Is Jack still here?- Yes.
- 謝謝。Jack還在這裡麼？- 是的。
[ Clears Throat ]
[清喉嚨]
[ TV:Announcer ]Shot on the way to the 1 1 8.
[電視播音：去118道上的槍擊...]
[ Mrs. Erganian ]Look what the cat dragged.
看看貓給拽的。
- Hi, everybody. Sorry.- Hey.
- 嗨，大家好。抱歉啊。- 嗨。
[Jack ]Somebody finally arrived.
某人終於來了。
You finally got here. Mr. Prompt.
你終於到了。飛毛腿先生。
- Oh, remember my kids? Alex, Helen?- Hi. How are you?
- 哦，記不記得我的孩子們？Alex, Helen?- 嗨，你們好。
We were thinking maybe you wentthe wrong way,you went to Tijuana...
我們還在想你是不是走錯了路，跑到墨西哥的提哇納去了...
- Right.- and they don't let you back.
- 對。- 然後他們不放你回來。
- Yes! Yes!- [ Laughing ] Daddy!
- 是啊，是啊！- 爸爸！
- I had to bribe them.- [ Continues Laughing ] Hey, Miles.
- 我不得不行賄他們。- 嗨，Miles。
Hey. How are you, Christine?
嗨，你好，Christine。
- [ Kiss ]- Yeah, the freeway was unbelievable.
高速公路塞的讓人難以置信。
Unbelievable.It was bumper-to-bumper the whole way.
真是難以置信，一路上車擠車的。
People getting an early starton the weekend, I guess.
我想大家週末出門都比較早。
Granted, I got a late start, but--
所以我就晚點出來，可還是--
Well, we're just glad you made it.
好了，我們都很高興你能來。
Christine, why don't youask Miles about the cake?
Christine, 你為什麼不問問Miles關於蛋糕的事？
- Oh, good idea. Come with me.- What's this?
- 好主意。跟我來。- 怎麼回事？
We don't really have time for that,'cause we gotta hit the road.
我們可能沒時間了，我們馬上得出發了
- [ Christine ] Oh, come on.!It's just gonna take a second.!- Yeah.
- 哦，來吧。就一秒鐘的事。- 就是。
[ Miles ]Mmm.
嗯。
Jack tells us you are publishing a book.Congratulations.
Jack告訴我們說你正在出版一本書。祝賀你。
- Uh--- Yes, congratulations.
-呃---是啊，祝賀你。
Yes, well, uh,it's not exactly finalized yet.
是的，不過，呃確切的說還沒有敲定呢。
- So-- There has been some interest, and--- Your friend is modest.
- 就是有人表示感興趣，而且--- 你的朋友很謙虛
Oh, come on, Miles.Don't be so modest. Indulge them.
得了 來吧，Miles.別那麼謙虛了，滿足一下他們吧。
- Don't make me out to be a liar.- What is the subject of your book?
- 別讓我當個撒謊的人啊。- 你的書是關於什麼主題的？
- Nonfiction?- Uh, no. It's-- It's a novel.
- 紀實的？- 呃，不，是--是小說。
- Fiction. Yes.- Oh.
- 虛構的。對。- 哦。
Although there is quite a bitfrom my own life...
不過有很多部分取材於我自己的生活...
so I suppose that, technically,some of it is nonfiction.
所以我想，從技術上講，算部分紀實吧。
Good. I like nonfiction.
好，我喜歡紀實的。
There is so much to knowabout this world.
這個世界有太多我們需要瞭解的。
I think you read something somebodyjust invented it, waste of time.
我覺得讀那些別人編造出來的東西簡直是浪費時間。
That's an interesting perspective.
這個觀點很有意思。
- So, which one do you like better?- Oh, well, I like them both.
- 那，你比較喜歡哪一個？- 呃，兩個都喜歡。
But, um, if pressed, I would have to saythat I prefer the dark.
不過，嘸，如果非要選的話，我得說我更喜歡那個黑的。
- [ Murmuring ]- [Jack ] Told ya.!
給你說過了！
- Bye-bye.- Bye.
-再見。-再見。
Bye.
再見。
Where the fuck were you, man? Huh?I was dying in there.
你他媽的剛才在哪兒？嗯？我在那兒都快死了。
- We're supposed to bea hundred miles away by now.- I can't help the traffic.
-本來我們現在都應該在100英里開外了。-交通堵塞，我也沒辦法。
Oh, come on. You're fucking hungover.You know you are.
哦，得了吧，你他媽的酒鬼。你自己明白。
Okay, there wasa tasting last night, yes.
好吧，我昨天晚上是嘗了一點，沒錯。
But I wanted to get us something nicefor the ride up. Check out the box.
我不過是想給我們的車旅準備點好東西。看那個盒子。
Why did you tell themthat my novel was being published?
你幹嗎告訴他們我的小說已經在出版了？
- 'Cause you said you had it all lined up.- No, I didn't. No. No.
-因為你說過你都聯繫好了。-沒有，我沒說過，沒有。
What I said was that there wassome interest at Conundrum.
我說的是"迷題"出版社的人表示有興趣。
- Yeah. Conundrum.- And that one of the editorswas passing it to a senior editor.
-對。"迷題"。-那個編輯要把小說遞給高層編輯。
Sounds pretty good to me.Sounds like you're in.
我覺得聽上去不錯。聽上去你已經搞定了。
No. It's a long shot.
沒有，希望並不大。
Besides, Conundrum,it's just a small specialty press.
再說，"迷題"只是一家小的專業出版社。
I'm not gonna get my hopes up.
我不打算抱太大希望。
You know? I've stopped caring.
你知道，我已經不再關心這事了。
The hell with it.I have stopped caring.
算了吧。我已經不再關心了。
It sounds like it's gonna happen this time.I mean, I can feel it.
聽起來好像這次能成。我是說，我能感覺到。
I think this is the one. Huh?
我想就是這次了。嗯？
I'm really proud of you, man.
我真為你感到驕傲，夥計。
- Don't open that now. It's warm.- Why not?
-現在別打開。還熱著呢。-為什麼不行？
Jack, that is a 1992 Byron.It's really rare. Okay?
Jack, 這可是1992年的Byron酒。這可是非常稀罕的。懂麼？
- I've been saving it. Don't--- All right. I won't open it.
-我一直存著它。別打---好的，我不打。
- [ Cork Pops ]-Jack!
-Jack!
- [ Chuckling ]- Half of it gone.
浪費了一半。
Hey, shut up. Okay?
嗨，閉嘴行不行！
Here's to a great week.
祝我們度過愉快地一周！
- Come on.- [ Champagne Pouring ]
來吧。
Yes. Absolutely.
嗯，絕對。
Despite your crass behavior...
雖然你很蠢...
I'm actually gladwe're getting this time together.
我還是很高興我們這次能一起來
Yeah. Me too.
對。我也這樣想。
I've been looking forward to thisfor a long time.
我期待這一天已經很久了。
- Was beginning to thinkit was never gonna happen.- Man! That's tasty!
-我還以為這一天永遠也不會來呢。-哎呀，味道真不錯！
That's 1 00% pinot noir.Single vineyard.
百分之百加州黑皮諾(pinot noir)葡萄單一品種的葡萄園。
They don't even make it anymore.
他們現在都不造這種酒了。
- Pinot noir?- Mm-hmm.
-黑皮諾葡萄？-嗯。
- Then how come it's white?- Oh,Jesus.
-那怎麼這是白色的？-哦，上帝啊。
Don't ask questions like thatup in wine country.
可別在葡萄酒園問這樣的問題。
- They'll think you're some kind of dumbshit.-Just tell me.
-他們會以為你是弱智呢。-告訴我麼。
Color in red winescomes from the skins.
紅葡萄酒的顏色來自葡萄皮。
This juice, on the other hand,is free run...
這個酒的葡萄汁不一樣，是自然流出的,不是擠壓的...
so that there's no skin contactduring fermentation--
所以在發酵的時候不會接觸到葡萄皮--
[ Miles ]Did you read the latest draft, by the way?
對了，你有沒有看過我最近的草稿？
- [Jack ] Oh,yeah.yeah.- And?
-嗯，看過了，看過了。-覺得怎樣？
It's great.
非常棒。
I mean, there are so many improvements.It's much tighter.
我是說，有很多出改動。結構更加緊湊了。
Just seems-- I don't know,more congealed or something.
就是看上去--不知道，好像更凝固了似的。
Mm-hmm. What about the new ending?Did you like that?
嘸。新的結局怎麼樣？你喜不喜歡？
Oh, yeah. New endingvastly superior to the old ending.
哦，對，新結局比老的那個結局好太多了。
There is no new ending.
就根本沒有新結局。
Page 7 50 on is exactly the same.
從750頁以後就沒有改動。
Well, maybe it just seemed new...
噢，那大概是看著象新的吧...
because everything leading up to itwas so different?
難道是因為所有導致結局的情節都變了？
Yeah! That must be it!
對！肯定是這個原因！
Whoa. Why are we getting off?
哇。我們為什麼要下車？
- Uh, I just wanna make one quick stop.- For what?
-呃，我想停一下。-幹什麼？
- I just thought we could saya quick hello to my mother.- Your mother?
-我想我們可以去和我媽媽打個招呼。-你媽媽？
Look, it's her birthday tomorrow.Okay?
看，明天是她生日。好麼？
- And I don't feel right driving byand not stopping in.- Okay.
-我覺得路過不進去拜訪挺不對的。-好吧。
- It'll take a second.She's right off the freeway.- Okay.!
-馬上就好。她就住在高速公路邊上。-好吧！
I didn't know it was her birthday.How old is she gonna be?
我不知道是她生日。她今年多大年紀了?
Uh, oh... 70-something.
呃，嗯...70--多吧。
[ Groans ]
[抱怨聲]
Oh. Here, hold thesefor just a second.
噢，這個，幫我那一下。
Thank you.
謝謝。
[ Doorbell Rings ]
[門鈴響]
- Surprise.!- Surprise!
-驚喜！-驚喜！
- Happy birthday, Mom!- Happy birthday!
-生日快樂，媽媽！-生日快樂！
Oh, my God! Miles! And Jack!
哦，上帝啊！Miles!Jack!
What a surprise!
真是個驚喜！
I can't remember the last timeyou brought me flowers!
我都不記得上次你給我帶花是什麼時候了！
Happy birthday, Mom.
生日快樂，媽媽。
They're from both of us.[ Chuckling ]
花是我們倆共同送的。
- A famous actorbringing me flowers for my birthday!- Right? Yeah!
-一個著名的演員給我的生日獻花？-是麼？是的！
- Don't I feel special?- [Jack ] And champagne.!
-我感到非常特別。-還有香檳！
- Famous actor's getting married next week, Mom.- Oh, that's right!
-這個著名的演員下周要結婚了，媽媽。-噢，對了。
Isn't that nice.
真是太好了。
I hope that girl knowshow lucky she is...
我希望那個女孩能知道自己有多幸運...
marrying no lessthan Derek Sommersby.
嫁給了一個像Derek Sommersby一樣的人。
Gosh, that was, like, 1 1 years ago,Mrs. Raymond.
天哪，那是大概11年前了吧，Raymond太太。
- Well,you were wonderful in that show.!- [ Laughs ]
反正，你在那個電視劇裡特別棒！
Why that didn't make you the biggestmovie star in the world is a sin!
那個劇沒讓你成為世界上最紅的影星真是罪過！
Oh, now, Miles...
哦，現在，Miles...
why didn't you tell me you were comingand bringing this handsome man?
為什麼不告訴我你來是給我帶來這個英俊的男人？
Look how I'm dressed!
看我打扮得多好！
I've gotta run and put my face on.
我得快點去化化妝。
You look fabulous, Mrs. Raymond.
你看上去很美，Raymond太太。
Oh, stop it!
哦，別這樣！
- Make yourselves comfortable.- [ TV:Announcer, Faint ]
你們隨便點。
- You boys hungry?- Yeah, I'm hungry.
-你們餓不餓？-嗯，我餓了。
[ TV:Announcer Continues ]Along with the battle casualties...
[電視播音員：隨著戰爭傷亡人數...]
Just a snack.
一點零食就可以了。
the Germans lost almost a million men.
[德國損失了一百萬人。]
To replace them, Hitler turnedto his last resort of manpower.
[為了補充人員希特勒不得不轉向最後的人力來源。]
This is delicious, Mrs. Raymond.Absolutely delicious.
這真好吃，Raymond太太。絕對好吃。
- Mmm.- They're just leftovers.
-唔。-只是剩下的而已。
[ Chuckles ]I-Is this chicken?
呃，這是雞肉麼？
I could have made something fancier...
我本來可以做些更花哨的吃的...
if a certain someone had let me knowthat a certain someone...
如果某人讓我事先知道某人...
was coming for a visitand bringing a certain special friend.
要來拜訪而且要帶一個特殊的朋友。
It was a surprise, Mom.
這是一個驚喜，媽媽。
And I could've already put clean sheets...
而且我還可以換上乾淨的床單
on the other bed and the foldout.
鋪在另外那張床上和折疊床上。
You are staying.
你們留下吧。
Wendy, Ron and the twins are picking us upat 1 1 :30 to go to brunch at the Sheraton.
Wendy, Ron 和雙胞胎11：30來接我們去喜來登吃早午餐。
They do a magnificent job there.
他們在那有一份極好的工作。
- You talked to Wendy?-Just now.
-你和Wendy講了？-就剛才。
She's thrilled! And the twins--
她高興極了！雙胞胎們--
No, no, I bet. I bet. Yeah.
不，不，不要了。我肯定不要。
Well, you know,Jack is pretty eagerto, uh, to get up to, um--
那，你看，Jack很想--呃--去， 唔--
[ Stammering ]You know.
你知道的。
Uh, but, yeah, absolutely.We'll see how it goes.
呃，不過，對，當然。我們看看怎麼樣。
Well, you boys do what you want.
那好吧，你倆想怎樣就怎樣吧。
I just thought it would be nice for usto be together as a family on my birthday.
我只是覺得在我生日的時候，我們能像一家人那樣聚在一起挺好的。
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
唔。唔。
I'll be right back.
我馬上回來。
[ Drawer Slides Closed ]
[開關抽屜]
[ Sighs ]
[嘆氣]
And what was that other one you did?
你拍的另外那個叫什麼來著？
The one where you were the jogger.
就是你演一個慢跑的人。
Oh, that was for, um, Spray 'n Wash.
哦，那個是，呃，Spray 'n Wash清潔劑廣告。
Spray 'n Wash! That's the one!
Spray 'n Wash！就是這個！
Gosh. I remember the girl that wasin it with me. She was somethin'.
天哪。我記得那個和我一起拍這個的女孩，她可真是個尤物。
[ Mrs. Raymond ]I just remember you jogging.
我就記得你慢跑來著。
[Jack Laughing ]Whoo-hoo!
嗚噢！
[ Mrs. Raymond ]So, when's the wedding?
那，婚禮什麼時候？
Next Saturday, Mom.Remember? We told you.
下週六，媽媽。不記得了？我們告訴過你的。
And Miles is my best man, Mrs. Raymond.My main man.
Miles是我的伴郎，Raymond太太。我最重要的人。
Miles, when are you goingto get married again?
Miles，你什麼時候再結婚啊？
I just got divorced, Phyllis.
我剛剛離婚，Phyllis.
[Jack ]Two years ago, buddy.
已經兩年了，夥計。
You should get back together...
你應該跟她和好...
with Victoria.
跟Victoria.
She was good for you.
她對你很合適。
She was good for you!
她對你很合適！
And so beautiful, and so intelligent.
而且那麼漂亮，那麼聰明。
You knew her, right?
你認識她，對麼？
[Jack ]Oh,yeah. Real well. Still do.
哦，對。關係不錯，現在還是。
I'm worried about you, Miles.
我很擔心你，Miles。
Do you need some money?
你需要錢麼？
[ Miles Whispering ]Jack.
Jack.
Jack, come on.
Jack, 過來.
[ TV:Man ]A rubber bag food slinger?
[TV:橡皮袋食品容器？]
Are you kidding me?
[你不是在開玩笑吧？]
Our super-amazing tree house...
[超神奇的樹上小屋...]
brought about by ourtwo-by-four technology--
[由我們的2x4技術帶給您--]
[ Whispers ]Jack! No, no, no, no. She'll wake up.
Jack!別，別，別。會把她弄醒的。
Who did this?
[誰幹的？]
- [ Boy ] I did!- [ Man ] What?
-[我幹的！]-[什麼？]
She was tired, silly.
[她太累了，傻瓜。]
Our ship was so high!
[我們的船真高！]
[ Girl ]They need a vacation!
[他們需要一次度假！]
Hamster holiday! Fun for all!
[倉鼠假日！大家都開心！]
Fuck! Too early in the morning for that.You know what I mean?
靠！大早上的幹那個是不是太早了？你明白我的意思麼？
Oh. She's a kid, for God's sake.
哦，她只是個孩子，看在上帝的份上。
As if she would even be attractedto guys like us in the first place.
好像她會喜歡我們這樣的男人似的。
Speak for yourself, man. I get chickslooking at me all the time. All ages.
是在說你自己吧，我可是總有靚妞注意的，各種年齡段的。
Dudes too.
甚至包括男人。
Well, it's not worth it.You pay too big a price.
喂，這樣不值得。你要付出很大代價。
- It's never free.- You need to get laid, Miles.
-沒有什麼是免費的。-你需要被操一頓，Miles.
- [ Laughs ]- That's gonna be my best-man giftto you this week.
這將是這星期我送給你的伴郎禮物。
I'm gonna get you laid.
我要讓你被操一頓。
Wonderful.
太好了。
I'm not gonna get you a gift certificateor a penknife or any of that other horseshit.
我不會給你送什麼禮券啊，袖珍小刀啊這樣的狗屎東西。
- I'd rather have a knife.- No.
-我寧可要個小刀。-不。
You have been officially depressedfor, like, two years now.
你已經被真真正正壓抑了大概兩年了。
You're a negative guy anyway,even back in college.
反正你就是個消極的人，在大學時就那樣。
- Mm-hmm.- And now it's worse.
-唔。-現在變得更糟了。
You're wasting away. Teaching Englishto fucking eighth-graders?
你真是屈才。給他媽的8年級學生教英語？
When they oughta be reading what you wrote.Your books, Miles.
他們什麼時候能讀到你寫的東西。你的書，Miles.
- I'm working on it.- [ Mutters ] Not working hard enough.
-我正在努力。-努力的還不夠。
- Are you still seeing that shrink?- I saw him on Monday.
-你還在看那個心理醫生麼？-我每週一去看。
I spent most of the timehelping him with his computer.
我大部分時間都花在幫他整電腦上了。
Well, I say fuck therapy and--What is that stuff you take? Xanax?
哼，我得說去他媽的心理治療--你在吃什麼藥？Xanax?
And Lexapro, yes.
對，還有Lexapro。
Well, I say fuck that too.You need to get your joint worked on, Miles.
哼，這些藥也去他媽的。你需要的是活動活動關節，Miles.
Okay,Jack--Jack--[ Clears Throat ]
好了，Jack--Jack--
This week is not about me.It is about you.
這個星期不是為我的，而是為你的。
I'm gonna show you a good time.
我要讓你享受一段美妙時光。
We're gonna drink a lot of good wine,we're gonna play some golf...
我們要喝很多很多美酒，我們要打高爾夫...
we're gonna eat some great food,enjoy the scenery...
我們要吃山珍海味，欣賞美景...
and we're gonna send you off in style,mon frere.
我們要像模像樣的和你告別，mon frere 我的兄弟。
And get your bone smooched.
要讓你的骨頭都被親遍。
You know what?
這麼著，
Let's take the Santa Rosa Road exitand hit Sanford first. Okay?
我們從聖羅莎路出口走，先去斯坦福酒園。怎麼樣？
Sounds good to me. I need a drink.
我覺得不錯。我正需要喝一杯。
These guys make top-notch pinotand chardonnay.
他們生產頂尖的皮諾酒和夏多利（chardonnay）酒。
One of the best producersin Santa Barbara County.
是聖巴巴拉一帶最好的產酒地之一。
- I thought you hated chardonnay.- No, no, no. I like all varietals.
-我還以為你討厭夏多利酒呢。-不，不不，我喜歡所有單品葡萄酒。
I just don't generally like the waythey manipulate chardonnay in California.
我只是不怎麼喜歡加利福尼亞處理夏多利酒的方式。
- Too much oak and secondarymalolactic fermentation.- Huh.
-用太多橡木和蘋果酸發酵。-哈。
You see, the reason that this regionis so good for pinot...
你看，這個地區很適合皮諾葡萄的原因...
is that the cold air off the Pacificflows in at night...
是晚間從太平洋來的冷空氣...
and it just cools down the berries.
讓漿果類植物涼快下去。
Pinot's a very thin-skinned grape.
皮諾是一種皮很薄的葡萄。
It doesn't like constant heat or humidity.Very delicate.
不喜歡持久高溫和潮濕。非常嬌貴。
[ Miles ]Let me show you how this is done.
我演示給你看該怎麼做。
First thing-- hold the glass up andexamine the wine against the light.
首先--舉起杯子對著燈光仔細看葡萄酒。
You're looking for color and clarity.
你要看的是顏色和純淨度。
-Just get a sense of it. Okay?- Okay.
-感覺一下它。好了麼？-好了。
Thick? Thin? Watery? Syrupy?
是稠還是稀？是水狀還是漿狀？
- Okay?- Okay.
-好了麼？-好了。
Now tip it.
現在傾斜一點。
What you're doing here is checking for colordensity as it thins out towards the rim.
現在要做的是在它靠近杯邊緣稀薄的地方檢查顏色的密度。
That's gonna tell you how old it is,among other things.
這會告訴你酒有多陳，當然還有其他的。
It's usuallymore important with reds.
通常這對紅酒更加重要。
- Okay?- Okay.
-好了麼？-好了。
Now stick your nose in it.
現在把鼻子伸進去。
- [ Sniffs ] Yeah?- Don't be shy.
-對麼？-不要害羞。
Really get your nose right in there.Really--
真的要把鼻子放進去。真的--
Mmm. A little citrus.
嘸， 一點橘子味。
Maybe some strawberry. Mmm.
好像還有點草莓。嘸。
Passion fruit. Mmm.
西番蓮果。嘸。
And-- Ah, there's just,like, the faintest...
還有-- 啊，好像還有點， 非常淡的...
[ Sniffs ]soupcon of like, uh, asparagus and--
很輕微的，像蘆筍， 還有--
There's a--just a flutter of, like, a--
有那麼點隱隱約約的，像--
like, a nutty Edam cheese.
像，堅果伊頓奶酪。
- Wow.- [ Sniffs ]
哇。
Mmm!
嘸。
- Strawberries. Yeah.- Good.
-草莓。對。-好。
- Strawberries. Not the cheese.- All right.
-草莓而已。沒有奶酪。-好吧。
Put your glass down.Get some air into it.
放下杯子。讓它進點空氣。
Oxygenating it opens it up.
氧化能將它打開。
It unlocks the aromas, the flavors.Very important.
釋放出香氣和滋味。非常重要。
- Smell again.- [ Both Inhaling ]
再聞。
Ah. That's what you dowith every one of'em.
啊。對每一杯都要這樣做。
- Wow. When do we drink it?- Now.
-哇。那我們什麼時候才能喝？-現在。
Mmm! Ahh.
嘸！啊。
- Mmm.- How would you rate this one, Miles?
-嘸。-你給這個酒打幾分，Miles?
Well, usually they start you on wineswith learning disabilities...
嗯，通常他們一開始給你的酒都像給有學習障礙的人準備的...
but this one is pretty damn good.
不過這個確實很好。
- This is the new one. Right, Chris?-Just released two months ago.
-這個是新酒，對吧，Chris?-兩個月前才出的。
- Nice job.- We like it.
-很不錯。-我們都喜歡。
You could work in a wine store,Miles.
你可以在葡萄酒店工作，Miles.Miles.
Mmm. Yeah.That'd be a good move.
唔，是啊。可能是個好出路。
[ Chuckles ]
[咀嚼聲]
Are you chewing gum?
你在嚼口香糖麼？
Do you think I'm making a mistakemarrying Christine?
你覺得我和Christine結婚會不會是個錯誤？
Whoa!
哇嗚！
Do you think I'm doing the right thing, Miles?Tell me the truth.
你覺得我做的對麼， Miles?說實話。
I mean, you've been there.
我的意思是，你是過來人。
Well, you know, I-- I think that youwaited for some good reason...
嗯，是這樣，我認為你曾經的等待很有道理...
and that you proposed to Christinefor some good reason...
你向Christine求婚也很有道理...
so I think it's great.
所以我覺得這是很好的事。
It's time.
是時候了。
I mean, you gotta have your eyes open,that's all.
我是說，你得把眼睛睜大點，這就行了。
I mean, look at me.I thought Victoria and I were set for life.
我的意思是，你看看我。我原以為我和Victoria能安穩過一輩子。
Christine's dad,he's really been talking to me...
Christine的爸爸，他居然跟我談了...
about bringing me into his property business,showing me the ropes.
讓我加入他的房地產生意，傳授給我其中的竅門。
Which is something, considering how longit took him to get over my not being Armenian.
這可意義重大。想想他用了多長時間才接受了我不是亞美尼亞人的事實。
So I'm thinking about it.
所以我總在想。
But I don't know.
不過我也不知道。
Might get a little incestuous.
可能會有點亂。
But Mike does great.A lot of high-end commercial stuff.
不過Mike做的很好。很多高端的商業東西。
- So you're gonna stop acting?- No way! No.
-那你以後就放棄表演了？-不可能，不會。
This would just provide some stability.
這只是為了生活穩定。
I could always squeeze in a commercialor an audition here, there.
我總能擠出時間，時不時參加個廣告或者試演什麼的。
Keep myself in the game in casesomething really great came along.
我得保持狀態，萬一好機會來了呢。
We're not getting any younger, Miles.
我們都不再年輕了，Miles.
No. No.
對，不再了。
- Hey, hey, hey.!- Hey.
嗨，嗨，嗨！嗨。
- Miles!- Sir.
-Miles!-先生。
- Long time no see.- Gary, nice to see you.
-好久不見了。-Gary, 很高興見到你。
- When's your novel coming out?We all wanna read it.- Soon, soon, soon.
-你的小說什麼時候出來？我們都等著讀呢。-馬上了，馬上了。
This is my buddyJack.He's getting married next week.
這是我的老朋友，Jack.他下星期要結婚了。
- My condolences, man.- What are you pouring tonight?
我哀悼一下，夥計。你們今晚去哪裡喝？
- Uh, we have got a lot of good stuff.- Mm-hmm?
-呃，我們有很多上等貨。-嗯哼？
Ah, we have the, uh, new Bien Nacido.You want a taste?
啊，我們有，呃，新的Bien Nacido酒。想嘗嘗麼？
[ Laughs ]Absolument.
那當然。
They make their own wine here.It's just outstanding.
他們這兒生產自己的酒，絕對不同凡響。
Very special. Thank you.
很獨特。謝謝。
Mmm!
嘸！
- Mmm.- So, what do you think?
-嘸。-你覺得怎麼樣？
Tighter than a nun's asshole.But good concentration. Nice fruit.
比修女的xx還要緊。濃度很好，原料不錯。
Pour us a couple, will ya.
給我們倒兩杯，好麼。
Yeah. It's tight.
對，是很烈。
There you are, gentlemen.
給，先生們。
I will leave you the bottle.And it is good to see you.
這瓶留給你了。很高興見到你。
Hey, man.Here's to my last week of freedom.
嗨，夥計。為我最後一周的自由。
It's gonna be great.
會很好的。
Here's to us.
為我們倆。
- Miles.- Mm-hmm?
- Miles.- 嗯哼？
Check out that chick.
看那個小妞。
Oh. Yeah. That's Maya.
哦。那是Maya。
- You know her?- Sure, I know Maya.
- 你認識她？- 當然，我認識Maya.
- You know that chick?- Yes.Jack, this is where I eatwhen I come up here.
- 你認識那個妞？-是的，Jack。我每次過來都在這兒吃飯。
You know?It's practically my office.
懂麼？這兒就好像我的辦公室。
And occasionally I have a drinkwith the employees, yeah.
偶爾我會和在這兒工作的人喝一杯，就是這樣。
Maya's great.She's worked here a year,year and a half.
Maya非常棒。她在這裡工作了一年，一年半了。
She's incredibly hot.
她性感的讓人難以置信。
Yes, she is.And nice. And married.
對，她是的。她很好，不過已經結婚了。
Check out the rock.
看她的大鑽戒。
Oh, that doesn't mean shit.
哦，那個屎都不算。
When Christine worked at Sushi Roku...
Christine在壽司店工作的時候...
she wore a big engagement ringto keep guys from hitting on her.
她一直戴著大個的訂婚戒指，以防男人們挑逗她。
Think it worked? Fuck no.How do you think I met her?
有用麼？他媽一點用沒有。你以為我是怎麼認識她的？
Well, this gal is married to somephilosophy professor at U.C. Santa Barbara.
嗯，這個女孩嫁的可是加州聖巴巴拉大學的哲學教授。
What's a professor's wife doing waitressing?Obviously that's over.
教授的太太做女招待說明什麼？明顯婚姻完蛋了。
Jack, you don't know anythingabout this woman.
Jack, 你並不瞭解這個女人。
Calm down. Let's just eat.
冷靜點。吃飯吧。
- Hey, Miles!- Oh! Hi, Maya.
- 嗨，Miles!- 哦，嗨，Maya.
- How are you?- I'm good. Good.
- 你好麼？- 我很好，很好。
You look great.Did you lose some weight?
你看上氣色不錯。是不是減肥了？
Uh... no, actually.
呃...事實上，沒有。
But... thank you.[ Chuckles ]
可是... 謝謝。
- Busy night, huh?- Sunday.
- 晚上很忙，嗯？- 星期天嘛。
You guys been out tasting?
你們倆出來品酒的？
Oh, you know it. You know it.
哦，你說對了，說對了。
Oh, this is my friend,Jack.Jack, Maya.
哦，這是我的朋友， Jack.Jack，這是Maya.
- Hiya.- Hi.
- 嗨，Maya.- 嗨。
Well, it's good to see you. Bye, Miles.
那，很高興見到你。再見，Miles.
Oh. Back to work.
哦，得回去工作了。
-Jesus, she is jammin'.- Yeah.
-上帝，她真勾魂。-是的。
And she's obviously into you.
很明顯她喜歡你。
What else do you know about her?
對她，你還瞭解什麼？
Well, she does know a lot about wine.
嗯，她很懂葡萄酒。
Ah. Now we're getting somewhere.
啊。看來有戲。
- She likes pinot.- Perfect!
-她喜歡皮諾酒。-絕配！
She's a fucking waitressin Buellton,Jack.
媽的，她只是Buellton的一個女招待，Jack.
How is that ever gonna work out?
我們怎麼可能？
You dick. Why do you have tofocus on the negative?
你這傢伙。怎麼你總是盯著壞的一面？
- See how friendly she was to you?- She works for tips.
- 看看她對你多親切？- 她只是為了小費。
You're blind, dude. Blind.
你瞎了，夥計。瞎了。
I can also recommend the ostrich steak.Very lean. Locally raised.
我還推薦鴕鳥排骨。肉很瘦。是本地養的。
Hey, Gary.
嗨，Gary.
- Highliner, please.- You got it.
- 再來點Highliner酒。- 好的。
- That's on us.- Yes, indeed.
- 我們請了。- 是的，真的。
Well, hey, guys. Do you mind?
嗨，大家介意麼？
- Oh, no, no, no.- You sure?
- 哦，不不。- 你確定？
Please. Light up, light up.
請便。點吧，點吧。
In fact, would you like to join us?
事實上，你願意和我們坐一起麼？
Sure.
當然。
- [ Clears Throat ]- So, how's that book coming, Miles?
嗯，你的書怎麼樣了，Miles?
I think you were almost finished with itthe last time we talked.
我想上次我們聊的時候你差不多快完成了。
- I finished it.- Good for you! Wow.
-我已經完成了。-你真棒！喔。
It's getting published.
現在正在出版。
That's, uh, actually whywe're up here celebrating.
這就是，呃，我們為什麼到這兒來慶祝。
Well, congratulations.
喔，祝賀你。
- That's fantastic!- Yeah.
-這真是妙極了！-是啊。
- Cheers.- Thanks.
-乾杯。-謝謝。
Are you a writer too?
你也是作家麼？
No, Maya, I'm an actor.
不，Maya, 我是個演員。
Really. What kind of stuff?
真的？演什麼？
Mmm, a lot ofTV.
嘸，很多電視。
I used to be a regularon a couple of series.
我原來是幾個劇集的常規演員。
But lately it's been a lot of commercial work.Nationals, mostly.
不過最近就是演很多廣告。大部分是給Nationals做的。
Anything I might know?
有沒有我可能知道的？
Perhaps. Do you recognize this?
可能。這個有沒有印象？
Now with a low, low5.8% A.P.R. financing!
現在只有很低，很低5.8% A.P.R. financing!5.8%的年利率！
[ Laughing ]That's hilarious!
太好笑了！
- You sound just like one of those guys.- Am one of those guys.
-你聽上去很像那種人。-我就是那種人。
- You are not.- He is.
-你不是。-他是的。
Consult your doctorbefore using this product.
使用本產品前，請咨詢醫生。
Side effects may include oily discharge...
副作用包括出油...
hives, loss of appetite,low blood pressure.
麻疹，食慾不振，低血壓。
If you have diabetesor a history of kidney trouble...
如果你有糖尿病或腎病史...
you're dead, asshole!
你必死無疑，笨蛋！
[ Chuckles ]Yeah.
對。
So, what are you guys up to tonight?
那，你們今天晚上打算幹什麼？
Oh, we're pretty wiped.
哦，我們已經挺累了。
I think we're just gonna go backto the motel and crash.
我想我們就回汽車旅館睡覺。
Yeah, I guess it'skind of a long drive up here.
對。我想開車來這兒有很長的路吧。
- Mmm.- Where are you staying?
-嘸。-你們住哪裡？
Uh, the Windmill.
呃，'風車'。
Windmill.
'風車'。
The girl is looking to party...
這女孩想要個派對...
and you tell her we're going backto the motel and crash?
你卻告訴她我們要回汽車旅館睡覺？
-Jesus, Miles!- Well, I'm tired,Jack.
-上帝啊，Miles!-唉，我累了，Jack.
- Aren't you tired?- The chick digs you, man!
-你難道不累麼？-那個女孩在試探你，笨蛋！
She lit up like a pinball machine...
她容光煥發像個彈球機...
when she found outyour novel was getting published.
在她聽說你的小說要出版的時候。
Now I have another lie to live down.
現在我不得不活在另一個謊言中。
- Thanks,Jack.-Just trying to get you a little action.
-謝謝你，Jack.-我只是想讓你行動起來。
I would appreciate a little bit of help.
我就很樂意接受一些幫助。
Didn't seem to me like that's whatwas going on. You were all over her.
我不覺得你那是在幫我。你把她全忘了。
Well, somebody had to do the talking.
噢，你就一定要教訓我。
And, by the way, I was right--she's not married.
而且，我猜對了--她的婚姻完了。
- How do you know?- No rock.
-你怎麼知道。-沒鑽戒。
When she came to the bar,she was sans rock.
她在酒吧的時候沒戴鑽戒。
Oh.
哦。
[ Sighs ]
[嘆息]
What's the plan for today, Miles?
今天的計劃是什麼，Miles?
Aha.
阿哈。
Good. Um, we head up north--
好。呃，我們先朝北去--
Begin the grape tour up there...
從那兒開始我們的葡萄之旅...
work our way south...
一路往南...
so that the more we drink...
這樣，我們喝的越多...
the closer we get to the motel.
就離我們的汽車旅館越近。
What's your problem?
你到底有什麼問題？
What is it?
怎麼了？
I'm going to get my nuton this trip, Miles...
我這次旅程一定要找點刺激，Miles...
and you are not gonnafuck it up for me...
你別壞我的事...
with all of your depression and anxietyand neg-head downer shit.
別用你那些沮喪，焦慮，那些他媽的負面思想。
[ Chuckles ]Oh.
哦。
Well, now the cards are on the table.
好啊，你都攤牌了。
Yes, they are.
對，沒錯。
- Ah.- And I am serious. Do not fuck with me, Miles.
-啊。-我是認真的。別壞我的事，Miles.
I am going to get laid before I get marriedon Saturday. Do you read me?
我要在週六結婚前操一頓。你懂不懂？
Sure, big guy. Absolutely.
懂，老大，當然懂。
Loud and clear.Whatever you say.
你講的每個字都聲音又大又清楚。
It's, uh,your party, evidently.
顯然，你在為你想要得派對生氣。
Why don't you just, uh--
你為什麼不乾脆，呃--
Uh, yeah. Why don't you just go out,and I'll catch a train back.
呃，對，你為什麼不乾脆自己去，我可以搭火車回去。
No, Miles!
不，Miles!
Man, this is our week to get crazy.
夥計，這周我們要瘋狂。
We should both be cutting loose.
我們兩個都要放縱一下。
This could be our last chance.This is our week, man.
這是我們最後的機會了。這是我們的一星期，夥計。
It's something we should share.
我們必須分享。
[ Man ]This is our Syrah.
這是我們的席拉（Syrah）酒。
Okay.
好。
- Ooh!- Yeah? Like that?
-喔！-好吧？喜歡麼？
That's a big one.
這個味很重。
[ Woman ] But it did sit with the skins forabout two weeks in an open-topped tank.
這酒要連葡萄皮一起在一個開口的酒桶中放兩個星期。
- So that would explain all the tannins, no?- Well, it is a young wine.
-難怪有單寧酸味兒，對不？-是啊，這酒還很新。
- So as the wine ages, the tannins will dissipate.- Right. Of course.
-就是說當酒越放越陳，單寧酸就會揮散掉。-對，當然。
- Excuse me for just a minute.- Good stuff.
-抱歉等我一下。-真是好東西。
Mmm. Fill up there, bub.
嘸，倒滿，小傢伙。
[ Woman ]This is our estate chardonnay.
這是我們園子的夏多利（chardonnay）酒。
Now, there's a girl who knows how to pour.What's your name?
哇，這個女孩才懂得怎麼倒酒。你叫什麼？
Stephanie.
Stephanie.
Stephanie. Nice.
Stephanie. 好聽.
So, what do you think?
你覺得怎麼樣？
Mmm. Quaffable.
嘸，可以一飲而盡。
But, uh, far from transcendent.
不過離卓越還差很多。
I like it. Tastes great.
我喜歡。味道很好。
Oak-y.
行了。
This is a cabernet franc.
這個是品麗珠紅葡萄酒（cabernet franc）
This is only the fifth yearwe've made this varietal.
我們生產這種單品葡萄酒才第五年。
Very few wineries around heredo a straight cab franc.
周圍很少有酒園子做純的cab franc酒。
It's from our vineyardsup in Santa Maria...
這是產自我們在聖瑪麗的葡萄園...
and it was a silver medal winner...
得過一次銀質獎...
at Paso Robles last year.
去年得了Paso Robles獎。
Hmm.
嗯。
Mmm.
嘸。
Well, I will tell you something.
那麼，我想說的是
I've come never to expect greatness froma cab franc, and this one is no different.
我從來就沒覺得cab franc酒有什麼妙處，這次也不例外。
It's kind of a hollow, flabby, overripe--
有一種空洞的，鬆弛的，熟過頭的感覺--
I don't know.Tastes pretty good to me.
我不知道。對我來說味道不錯。
So, um, do you live around here,Stephanie?
那，呃，你住這附近麼，Stephanie?
Yeah, up around Los Alamos.And I agree with you about cab franc.
對，就在Los Alamos附近。我同意你對cab franc酒的評價。
We're just over in Buellton.
我們剛去過Buellton酒園。
The Windmill Inn.
風車旅館。
- Oh, yeah?- Mmm.
-哦，是麼？-嗯。
Do you happen to know a gal named Mayathat works at The Hitching Post?
你有沒有碰巧認識一個叫Maya的女孩，她在The Hitching Post酒吧工作？
- Yeah. Sure. I know Maya. I know her real well.- Yeah? No shit?
-當然，我認識Maya，我和她很要好。-真的？沒騙人？
We had a drink with her last night.Miles knows her.
我們昨天晚上和她一起喝酒了。Miles認識她。
Yes. Could we move onto the Syrah, please?
對。我們能不能繼續嘗席拉酒？
Oh. Champing at the bit, huh?
哦。等不及了，嗯？
Sure.
當然。
This is our estate Syrah.
這個是我們園子的席拉酒。
You are a bad, bad girl, Stephanie.
你真是個壞壞的女孩，Stephanie。
I know. I need to be spanked.
我知道，我應該被打屁屁。
Excuse me.
失陪一下。
The Syrah?
席拉？
Hey. Hey. Get the trunk.
嘿，嘿，打開車後箱。
- You have the keys.- I do?
-你掏鑰匙。-我有鑰匙麼？
- Yeah.- In my pocket.
-對。-在我口袋裡。
- So, we're on.- What?
-這麼說，我們成了。-什麼。
Yeah. She called Maya, who's not workingtonight. So we're all going out.
對呀。她去叫Maya，她今晚不工作。我們一起出去。
- Wi-- With Maya?- Yeah.
-和，和Maya?-對。
She's been divorced a year now, buddy.
她離婚已經一年了，夥計。
This chick Stephanie?
那個叫Stephanie得女孩？
She's got it all goin' on.
她什麼都安排好了。
Well, she is cute, yeah.
嗯，她很可愛，對。
Cute? She's a fuckin' hottie.
可愛？她是他媽的辣妹。
And you almost tell her that I'm gettin' married?What's the matter with you?
你差點就告訴她我要結婚了？你怎麼了你？
- Nice, huh?- It's beautiful.
-很漂亮，噢？-非常美。
Yeah. Victoria and Iused to like this view.
對。Victoria和我原來很喜歡這裡。
You know,once we had a picnic here...
你知道，有一次我們在這裡野餐...
and we drank a '95 Opus One.
我們喝了一瓶95年的Opus One.
With smoked salmon and artichokes.But we didn't care.
就著煙熏三文魚和薊菜。不過我們不在乎。
Oh, man, she has the best palateof any woman I have ever known.
噢，天哪，她是我認識的味覺最好的女人。
She can even differentiateall different kinds of Italian wines.
她可以分辨出所有不同種類的意大利葡萄酒。
- Miles, there's something I gotta tell you.- [ Sighs ]
Miles，有些事我必須告訴你。
Victoria's coming to the wedding.
Victoria也要來參加婚禮。
Yeah, I know. You told me.I'm all right with it.
對，我知道。你告訴過我的。我不介意。
Yeah, but that's not the whole story.
是的，不過我沒全告訴你。
She got remarried.
她已經再婚了。
She what?
她什麼？
When?
什麼時候？
About a month ago.
大概一個月以前。
Maybe six weeks.
可能6個星期。
To that guy--that guy with the restaurant?
嫁給那個傢伙--那個開餐館的傢伙？
Miles?
Miles?
Miles.
Miles.
I'd like to go home now.
我想回家了。
Miles, get out of the car.
Miles，從車裡下來。
Would you drive meback to the motel, please?
請開車送我會旅館。
[ Sighs ]You know--
你知道--
She bringing him to the wedding?
她要帶他來參加婚禮？
What do you think?
你覺得怎麼樣？
Why didn't you tell meabout this before,Jack?
你為什麼不早點告訴我，Jack?
Because I knew you'd get so freaked outthat you wouldn't even come on this trip.
因為我知道你肯定要發瘋了那我們就不能一起來者趟旅行了。
But then I thought,this is the perfect place to tell you.
然後我想，這可能是我告訴你這件事最好的地方。
We're here to forget about all that shit.We're here to party, man.
我們來這裡就是為了忘掉那些狗屎事。我們來這裡就是為了派對的，夥計。
I'm gonna be a fucking pariah.
我是個可憐蟲。
Persona non grata.
不受歡迎的人。
Everybody's gonna be holding their breath,waiting to see if I get drunk and make a scene.
每個人都會屏住呼吸，等著看我喝多了出洋相。
No, no. No. Look.
不，不。 不，你看
I talked to Victoria. Okay?
我和Victoria談過了，好麼？
She's cool. Everybody's cool.
她很好。每個人都很好。
I'm sorry. You've been talking--
對不起，你已經和她談過了--
Behind my back...
背著我...
you've been talking about it?
你們談論？
What are you doing?
你幹什麼？
Come back here.
回來。
Miles!
Miles!
- Come here. Give me that bottle.- Back off,Jack.
-回來。把酒瓶給我。-退後，Jack.
- Come on--- Back off, man!
-好了---退後，笨蛋！
- Give me that bottle.- No.
-把酒瓶給我。-不。
Miles.
Miles.
Miles!
Miles!
[ Panting ]
[喘息]
[ Gasps ]
[上氣不接下氣]
- [ Coughs ]- [ Bottle Lands ]
-[咳嗽]-[酒瓶墜地]
[ Continues Panting ]
[喘息]
[ TV:Announcer ] A lot of peopleout there think they can make it.
[TV: 很多人認為他們能成功]
What better thing in life is to chase thedream and not be afraid of going after it?
[生活中還有什麼比敢於追求夢想更好的？]
James Lepp next to play.Chance for a birdie and a five-shot lead.
[James Lepp 接下來上演]
I'm gonna go for a swim,get the blood flowing. You wanna come?
我要去游泳，讓血液流通。你來麼？
No. I wanna watch this.
不，我想看電視。
Okay.
好吧。
Should start this ball one or two inchesoutside the left edge.
[應該把球放在左邊一兩英吋外]
[ Spectator Whispers ]Go in.
[進了。]
[ Crowd Groans ]
[觀眾歡呼]
- [ Announcer] Great putt.- [ Analyst ] Absolutely. Great speed.
-[漂亮的一擊]-[絕對漂亮，速度很好]
[ Spraying ]
[噴香水]
- [Jack ] Miles.- [ Spraying Continues ]
Miles.
Oh, Miles. Time to get up.
哦，Miles, 該起床了。
[ Groans ]
[嘀咕聲]
This fuckin' chick in theJacuzzi--
靠，那個女孩在Jacuzzi--
Oh, dude!
哦，好傢伙！
This place is wide open.I'm goin' fuckin' nuts up here, man.
那個地方很寬敞，我就打算在那兒干，夥計。
- Hey, what should I wear?- I don't know.
-嘿，我應該穿什麼？-我不知道。
Something casual, but nice.They think you're a writer.
休閒一些的，不過要好看。她們覺得你是個作家。
[ Mutters ]Right. Okay.
好的，好的。
Mmm.
嘸。
Do you have any other shoes?
你還有沒有別的鞋了？
Uh-uh.
呃-呃。
Hmm.
嗯。
[ Cell Phone:Escalating Tones ]
[手機鈴響]
- [ Exhales ]- Hey, honey.
嗨，親愛的。
Yeah, I was just calling to check in.
噢，我就是打電話問問你怎麼樣了。
Miles and I are getting readyto go to dinner.
我和Miles要準備出去吃晚飯了。
Probably stay out late, so I just thoughtI'd call and say good night now.
可能要在外面待很晚，所以我想現在打電話給你說晚安。
Yeah. I miss you too.
是的，我也想你。
Yeah. I love you too.
是的，我也愛你。
Just try to be your normal,humorous self. Okay?
盡量像你正常時候一樣，幽默一點，好麼？
The guy you were before the tailspin.Do you remember that guy?
像你感情崩潰前那樣。你還記得那個時候的你麼？
People love that guy.
大家都喜歡那個時候的你。
And don't forget--your novel is coming out in the fall.
而且別忘了--你的小說秋天就要面市了。
Oh. Really? How exciting.What's it called?
哦，真的麼？多麼讓人激動啊。叫什麼名字？
Come here, Miles. Come here.
過來，Miles,過來。
Do not sabotage me.
不要破壞我的事。
If you wanna be a fuckin' lightweight,then that's your call.
如果你想當他媽的爛人，你就自己當爛人。
- But do not sabotage me.- Oh, aye, aye, cap'n. You got it.
-但是不要破壞我。-哦，是，是，船長。我保證。
And if they wanna drink merlot,we're drinkin' merlot.
如果她們想喝merlot酒，我們就喝merlot酒。
If anybody orders merlot, I'm leaving.I am not drinking any fucking merlot!
如果誰要是點了merlot酒，我馬上走人。我才不喝他媽的merlot呢！
Okay, okay. Relax, Miles.
好了，好了，放鬆，Miles.
Jesus. No merlot.
上帝啊，不要merlot酒。
Did you bring your Xanax?
你有沒有帶你的抗抑鬱藥？
- [ Pills Rattle ]- All right.
好的。
Come here.
過來。
Do not drink too much.Do you hear me?
別喝太多。聽見沒？
I don't want you passing outor going to the dark side.
我可不想你醉倒，或撒酒瘋。
- No going to the dark side!- Okay!
-不撒酒瘋！-好的。
Hi.Just looking for some friends.
嗨。我們找朋友。
- #[ LightJazz ]- [ Murmuring, Chattering ]
[輕爵士樂]
Good evening, ladies.How are you?
晚上好，女士們。你們好麼？
- Hi, Miles.- [ Stephanie ] Good. How are you?
-嗨，Miles.-很好，你呢？
Hello, Maya.[ Sighs ]
Hello, Maya.你好，Maya.
- You look gorgeous. You both do.- [ Maya ] Thank you.
-你看上去美極了。你們倆都是。-謝謝。
- You're not so bad yourself.- Thanks. Thanks.
-你自己也不錯。-謝謝，謝謝。
[Jack ]So, what's good here?
那，這有什麼好酒？
- What is this you're drinking?- Oh, this is the Fiddlehead sauvignon blanc.
-你們喝的是什麼？-哦，這個是長相思（sauvignon blanc）。
- Ah, I see. Is it good?- Try it.
-啊，知道了。好喝麼？-你試試。
- What time did you close up at Ka-- Is it--- Kalyra.
-你們酒吧幾點關，叫什麼來著？- Kalyra.
- Kalyra.- I actually got out of there pretty good,around 5:30, 6:00.
- Kalyra.-其實我很順利就出來了，大概5:30，6點的樣子。
- Still had some stuff to do.- Miles and I, we were--
-還有點事情要做。-Miles和我，我倆--
- That's nice.- It's aged 1 2 months in oak.
-很好。-這是在橡木中放了12個月的。
- French oak.- Sauvignon blanc?
-法國橡木。-長相思酒？
Huh. Interesting. It's good.
嗯，有趣。很好。
I know the winemaker.She comes into the restaurant all the time.
我認識這個造酒商。她經常去我們餐廳。
- What do you have to do to close up?- I close up the register.
-你關門前都要幹什麼？-我要關閉登記處。
Clean up, put some stuff away.Then put the glasses out for the next day.
打掃一下，把一些東西放好。再把第二天的酒杯準備好。
- Right.-Just... small stuff.
-對。-就是些...小事。
Uh, hints of clove.
有一點點丁香味。
- Right?- Yes! I know. I love that.
-對麼？-是的，我知道，我很喜歡。
Yeah. Mmm.
對。嘸。
Sorry. It's good.
對不起。很好。
- No, no. We'll get you a glass.- Ah! Now we're thinking.
-沒關係。我們再給你要一杯。-啊，我們要開喝了。
Good. [ Chuckles ] Okay.
好。
[ Stephanie ]Oh, that's-- that--
哦，那個--那個--
Oh, he can say it,and it's not disgusting?
哦，他可以說出來呀，不是很噁心.
I didn't hear him say that.
我沒聽見他說。
- Whenever I say something he said--- [ Laughs ] Very good.
-每次我重複他說的話---非常好。
No, actually-- No. That one.N-Not this one--
不，事實上，是那個。不是這個--
[Jack, Stephanie Laughing ]
[笑聲]
[Jack ]I'm having that too.
我也有那個。
- Right?- Oh, yes.
-什麼？-哦，是的。
That's what I'm saying.
那是我要說的。
For our soup we have corn chowder...
湯我們有玉米雜燴...
and for our entrees we have medallionsof pork dusted with black truffles...
主菜我們有大豬排澆太妃糖...
served with a root vegetable foulonand wasabi whipped potatoes.
配菜有菜根和芥末土豆。
And finally--
最後--
- [ Maya ] I have to explain my credentials.- [ Stephanie ] Yes.!
-我不得不解釋我的證件。-對！
Miles, what does this remind you of?.
Miles,這個讓你想起什麼？
"Red wine. Red wine."
「紅酒， 紅酒。」
[Jack ]He was brought up on a lot of charges.
他是在一大堆指責中長大的。
- Yeah?- I mean, with the yellow light.
-是麼？-我的意思是警告。
Right.
對。
After all, tonightwe are celebrating Miles's book deal.
總之，今晚我們要慶祝Miles的新書。
- Published author.- Oh! Wow!
-出版作家。-哦，哇！
Wow, Miles.!
哇嗚，Miles!
- Ohh.!- [ Maya ] Well, in that case--
-哦！-那麼，那樣的話--
[ Conversations Continue,Faint, Indistinct ]
[談話聲淡去]
And then they think you have no idea.You have no control over it.
然後他們就以為你沒有任何想法，無法控制局面。
[ Maya, Stephanie Laughing ]
[Maya, Stephanie笑]
[ Miles ]Ancient way of treating the grape.
古老的處理葡萄的方式。
Now it's a modern wayof treating the grape.
現在這種是現代的處理葡萄的方式。
It's a traditional way of dealing with wine.It's a controversial way.
那時傳統的釀酒方式，一種有爭議的方式。
[ Stephanie ]So everyone's going back to that.
然後大家都回去了。
It's just that there'sa certain constant lapping.
只是總有些重疊的地方。
- It's not a-- It's a fishing lake.- Mm-hmm.
-那個不是--那是個釣魚的湖。-嗯哼。
Your lips look soft.
你的嘴唇很柔軟。
[ Phone:Line Ringing ]
[電話鈴響]
- The whole area is--- Oh, no. You mean, like, what it was used for?
-總的來說---哦，不。你的意思是，好比，這個是幹什麼用的？
- What do they call the--- [ Phone:Line Continues Ringing ]
-他們為什麼要打電話--
Malibu-- It's Malibu Canyon.
馬裡布--是馬裡布峽谷。
- [ Laughs ]- [ Phone:Line Continues Ringing ]
[笑聲][電話鈴聲]
I don't know what the hellI'm trying to say.
我也不知道我到底想說什麼。
- [ Sighs ]- [ Ring ]
[鈴聲]
[ Exhales ]
[喘息聲]
- [ Line Picks Up ]- [ Woman ] Hello?
喂？
Victoria?
Victoria?
Miles?
Miles?
Well, well, well, well, well.Victoria. How the hell are ya?
好，好，好，好。Victoria， 你怎麼樣啊？
What-- Uh-- What's on your mind?
什麼--呃--你想幹什麼？
Oh, nothin'. I--[ Chuckles ]
哦，沒什麼。我--
Just heard that you got remarried.
剛聽說你又結婚了。
Congratulations. I, uh--
恭喜啊。我，呃--
Boy, I didn't think you had the stomachfor another go-around.
哦，我可沒想到你還有胃口再來一遍。
Oh, Miles, you're drunk.
哦，Miles， 你喝醉了。
Oh,just a little local pinot,you know.
噢，就一點本地的皮諾，你知道的。
A little burgundy. That old Cotes de Beaune.[ Laughs, Clears Throat ]
一點勃艮第（burgundy），那種老的法國伯爾尼紅酒（Cotes de Beaune）。
- Where are you?- Uh, a little place in Los Olivos.
-你在哪裡？-呃，一個Los Olivos的小地方。
New owners. Cozy ambience, uh--
店主是新的，環境很溫馨，呃--
Excellent food too.You should, uh-- You should try it.
吃的東西也非常好。你應該，呃--你應該試試。
I thought of you at the, uh,Hitching Post last night.
我想起了你，呃昨天晚上在Hitching Post的時候。
Hello?
喂？
- Miles, don't call me when you're drunk.- No, it's--
-Miles,不要在喝醉的時候給我打電話。-沒有，只是--
All right, I just--I wanted to let you know...
好吧，我只是--想讓你知道...
that I have decidednot to come to the wedding...
我已經決定不去參加婚禮了...
so just in case you were dreading some sort of,you know, run-in or something like that...
所以，如果你原來擔心會發生什麼像吵架這種事
well, you worry no more...
那你現在不用再擔心了...
because I'm not gonna be there.
因為我不會去那兒的。
It's my little wedding giftto you and what's-his-name.
這是個小小的結婚禮物，送給你和--他叫什麼來著。
What is his name?
他叫什麼？
Ken.
Ken.
Ken! Right.
Ken!太好了。
I'm gonna hang up now, Miles.
我要掛了，Miles.
No-- You know, it's just--I-I-I heard about this...
不--你知道，只不過--我剛聽說這件事...
for the first time, uh, today.
今天第一次聽說。
Uh, your getting remarried, that is.
呃，你又結婚了。就是這樣。
And, uh, I was kind of taken aback.
呃， 我就是有點嚇到了。
Just... hard to believe.
真是...難以置信。
[ Chuckles ]
[笑]
I guess I thought maybethere was still a chance...
我原來還以為可能還有一點點希望...
for us somewhere down the road.
沒準兒什麼時候我們倆。
And I just, uh--[ Sighs ]
我就是，呃--
- Miles.- Huh?
- Miles.- 嗯？
Maybe it is betterif you don't come to the wedding.
也許你不去婚禮更好一些。
All righty, Vicki. Whatever you say.
沒問題，Vicki,你怎麼說都行。
You're the boss.
我聽你的。
Huh? I don't know.
嗯？ 我不知道。
[ Laughs ]Welcome back.
歡迎回來。
Take it easy.
放鬆點。
[ Miles Sighs ]
[Miles嘆氣]
- Are you okay, Miles?- Yes. I'm fine.
-你還好吧，Miles?-是的，我很好。
Thank you.
謝謝。
- Excuse us, gentlemen.- Excuse us.
-失陪一下，先生們。-失陪一下。
[Jack ]Sure.
沒關係。
- Mmm.- All right.
-嘸。-好的。
Yeah. Don't take too long.
好，別太久了。
- All right.- Okay. Bye, girls. [ Chuckles ]
-好的。-好。再見。
What the fuck?What is up with you?
他媽的怎麼搞得？你怎麼回事？
- You remember our little talk outside?- Yeah--
-你還記得我們再外面談過的吧？-對--
- Get your shit together, Miles.- I'm fine. I'm fine.
-你他媽的打起精神來，Miles.-我沒事，我沒事。
Where were you?
你剛才去哪裡了？
Bathroom.
廁所。
Did you drink and dial?
你是不是有喝醉了去打電話？
Hmm?
嗯？
- No.- Why do you always have to do this?
-沒有。-你為什麼老這麼幹？
Victoria is gone. Gone.
Victoria已經飛了，飛了。
Poof!. In the wind.
噗，消失在風裡了。
I mean, you are blowing a greatopportunity here with Maya.
我的意思是，你正在毀掉一個和Maya在一起的好機會。
Maya-- Fuckin' Maya-- She's great!
Maya--靠 Maya--她很棒！
She's cool, she's funny, she knows wine.
她很好，風趣，又懂葡萄酒。
What is this morose, come-down bullshit?
什麼消沉鬱悶的狗屎東西？
These girls wanna party with us.
這些女孩要和我們派對。
Huh?
嗯？
And what was that 1 0-minute lectureon, what, Vouvrays?
還有你剛才滔滔不絕10分鐘講什麼？沃萊白葡萄酒？
Are you kidding me?Who gives a fuck?
你不是開玩笑吧？誰理你那個茬？
Let's just say that I'm uncomfortablewith the whole scenario.
這麼說吧，我對當前的整個情況很不爽。
Have you forgotten all the bad timesyou had with Victoria...
難道你忘了和Victoira一起的那些不愉快了麼？
how small she could make you feel?
她讓你覺得你很渺小？
Isn't that why you had the affairwith Brenda in the first place?
這難道不就是你先和Brenda搞婚外戀的原因麼？
Shut up. Shut your face. Shut up.
閉嘴。收起你的臭臉。閉嘴。
Have you even noticedhow Maya's looking at you?
你難道就沒有注意Maya看著你的樣子麼？
Now, come on, man.You've got her on the hook.
好了，夥計。你已經讓她上鉤了。
Reel her in.Let's ratchet this up a notch.
把她釣起來。釣的高一點。
Here. Drink some agua fria.
來，喝點agua fria.
- [ Mouths Words ]- Hey!
嗨！
- Hey!- Mmm.
-嗨！-嘸。
Ah. Well, so, uh,shall we get some dessert?
啊，那，呃，我們要不要點甜點？
Uh, well, we were thinking, um, uh,why don't we go back to my place?
呃，我們想，呃我們都去我家怎麼樣？
I've got wine, some insane cheeses,music, whatever.
我有葡萄酒，奶酪，音樂，什麼都有。
[ Laughs ]Yeah!
好呀！
[ Imitates Cat Snarling,Continues Laughing ]
[學貓叫，笑聲]
- [ Stephanie, Maya Laughing ]- Waiter!
-侍者！
Come here.
過來。
Uh-huh.
呃。
- One for you, three for me.- Mmm.
-給你一個，我三個。-嘸。
You sure you wanna do this?
你確定你想這樣麼？
[ Sighs ]
[嘆息]
#[ Stereo:Female SingingMid-tempo Ballad ]
[音樂聲]
- We're here!- [ Stephanie ] Hey.!
-我們來了！-嗨！
- Hey!- Where were you guys?
-嗨！-你們去哪兒了？
Oh, we took a couple of wrong turns,thanks to Magellan here.
噢，我們拐錯了幾個彎，多虧了還有麥哲倫。
- [ Whispers ] Hi.- Hi.
-嗨！-嗨！
- Oh, Miles.- Yeah?
-噢，Miles.-什麼？
- Maya's in the back,just past the kitchen.- Okay.
-Maya在後面，過了廚房就是。-好的。
- [Jack Chuckles ]- Thanks.
謝謝。
Hi.
嗨。
Hey.
嘿。
- Oh, has she got anything good?- Oh,yeah.
-哦，她有什麼好酒麼？-噢，是的。
Steph's way into pinots and Syrahs.
Stephanie對皮諾酒和席拉酒很著迷。
- Hey, Steph!- Yeah?
-嗨，Stephanie？-怎麼了？
- Can we really open anything we want?- Yeah,yeah. Anything.
-我們是不是想開哪瓶就開哪瓶？-對對，隨便。
Uh, except the Richebourg.
噢，除了那瓶Richebourg。
Richebourg? She has a Richebourg?Holy mackerel.
Richebourg？她居然有Richebourg？Holy mackerel.
I've completelyunderestimated Stephanie.
我真是低估了Stephanie了。
Oh, good Lord. Um, look at that.
噢，上帝，看這個。
[ Bottle Settles Onto Rack ]
[酒瓶放回架子]
I think... this guy's more our speed.
我想...這個酒更適合我們的口味。
Andrew Murray.
Andrew Murray.
Well, okay. All right.
好的。
So, what gems do you havein your collection?
那，你的收藏中有什麼寶貝？
Oh, it's really not muchof a collection, you know.
噢，其實都算不上什麼收藏。
I mean, more like a small gatheringin a cabinet.
我的意思是更像是放在櫃子裡的一點東西。
- [ Laughs ]- No, I've never really had the wallet for that.
我從來沒錢買那些。
I just have to live bottle to bottle.
我就是忍不住要一瓶一瓶的喝。
I've got things I'm saving, definitely.
不過我還是省了些下來，當然了。
I guess the star would bea 1961 Cheval Blanc.
我想起中的明星就是那瓶1961年的Cheval Blanc。
You've got a '61 Cheval Blanc,and it's just sitting there?
你有一瓶61年的Cheval Blanc，卻放在那裡不動？
- Yes, I do.- Go get it.
-是的，是的。-快去拿。
- [ Laughing ] Okay.- I'm serious! Hurry!
-好了。-我是認真的！快去！
All right. I would, I would.
好的，我會去拿的。
The '61 s are peaking right now, aren't they?That's what I've read.
61年的酒現在正是最好的時候，是吧？我從書上看的。
No, that's right, yeah.
不，對，是的。
It might be too late already.What are you waiting for?
可能都已經有點晚了。你還在等什麼？
Oh, I don't know.A special occasion with the right person.
噢，我不知道。一個特別的場合和最合適的人。
- It was supposed to be formy 1 0th wedding anniversary, but--- Mmm.
-本來是準備在結婚10週年的時候，但是---嘸。
You know, the day you opena '6 1 Cheval Blanc...
你知道，當你打開61年的Cheval Blanc的時候
that's the special occasion.
那就是那個特別的時候。
[ Wine Pouring ]
[倒酒]
So, uh, how longhave you been into wine?
嗯，你對葡萄酒感興趣有多長時間了？
I got serious about seven years ago.
從我認真開始算起有7年了。
- And what was the bottle that did it?- '88 Sassicaia.
-是哪瓶酒讓你開始的？-88年的Sassicaia。
- Ah.! Well, congratulations.- Mmm.
-啊。很好。恭喜。-嘸。
- Yeah.- That's very good.
-是啊。-非常好。
- Well--- That would do it. Yeah.
-很好---真能讓你著迷。是的。
Hmm.
嗯。
Mmm.
嘸。
Oh, wow, that's nice.That's very good.
哦，哇，真好。真是非常好。
We need to give it a minute,but that's really tasty.
我們應該多品一會兒，不過實在是味道太好了。
How about you?
你覺得呢？
I think they overdid it a little.
我覺得他們做的有點兒過了。
Too much alcohol.It overwhelms the fruit.
太多酒精味兒，把葡萄的味兒都蓋住了。
Huh.
唔。
Yeah. Yeah.
是的，是的。
I'd say you're right on the money.
我得說你對錢的態度是對的。
Very good. [ Chuckles ] Nice.
非常好。很好。
- Thank you.- Mmm.
-謝謝。-嘸。
Mmm! Is that Stephanie's kid?
嘸。那是Stephanie的孩子麼？
Oh. Yeah. That's Siena.
哦，是的。那是Siena.
- Oh, she's a sweetie.- Cute. Cute.
-哦，她是個小甜心。-很可愛，很可愛。
Where is she?
她現在在哪裡？
- She's at her grandmother's.- Oh.
-在她祖母家。-哦。
Steph's mom.She spends a lot of time over there.
在Stephanie的媽媽那裡。她經常待在那裡。
You got kids?
你有孩子麼？
Uh, me? No. No.
哦，我？沒有，沒有。
- No, I'd just fuck 'em up.- [ Laughs ]
沒有，我會把他們都帶壞的。
No, that was the one unpolluted partof my divorce-- no kids.
沒有，這是我的離婚中沒有被污染的部分--沒有孩子。
Yeah. Same here.
對。我也是。
Good.
很好。
Let's go in there.
我們出去吧。
[Jack ] Now, for a low, low4.8% A.P.R. financing--
現在，以很低很低的4.8%的年利率--
[ Stephanie Laughing ]
[ Stephanie 笑聲 ]
[ Stephanie,JackConversing, Indistinct ]
[ Stephanie,Jack談話聲 ]
[ Sighs ]
[ 嘆息 ]
[ Stephanie Laughing ]
[ Stephanie 笑聲]
Looks like our friendsare really hitting it off.
看起來我們的朋友們談的很投機。
- Yeah, I would say that.- [ Laughs ]
對，我也這麼覺得。
- Yeah.- [ Sighs ]
是的。
- [ Clears Throat ]- So, what's your novel about?
那，你的小說是關於什麼的？
What's my-- Oh, brother.
是我的--哦 兄弟。
Well, it's, uh--it's difficult to summarize.
嗯，這個，呃——這很難總結。
Um...
嘸...
it starts out as a kind offirst-person narrative...
開始是一種第一人稱敘述...
about a guy taking careof his father after a stroke.
一個男人照顧他中風後的父親。
- Oh.- It's kind of based on, uh, personal experience.
-哦。-這個有點根據我的個人經歷。
But only-- only loosely.
不過只是--只是大體上。
What's the title?
小說名字叫什麼？
The Day After Yesterday.
昨天的明天。
Oh. You mean today.
哦，你是說今天。
Um... uh, yeah.I mean, r-right. But it's more--
呃...呃，是的。我是說，對。不過沒那麼簡單--
So it's about, like,death and mortality, or--
是不是關於，比如，死亡和永恆，或者--
[ Sighs ]Uh, yeah--
哦，對--
Y-- Not really.
對，不過也不全是。
I, uh-- It de-- It jumps around a lot.
我，哦--用了很多跳躍式結構。
That's what it's about, in a way.You know what I mean?
這是我想表達的，從某種意義上。你懂我的意思麼？
You start to see everythingfrom the point of view of the father.
你開始以父親的眼光看周圍的一切。
And, uh, a lot of other things happen--parallel narratives.
並且，呃，同時有很多其他事情發生了--並列敘述。
[ Laughs ]It's kind of a mess.
有點亂。
And then, eventually,the whole thing sort of evolves...
然後，最終整個事情向前發展...
or devolves...
或者衰退...
into this sort ofRobbe-Grillet mystery.
最後成為一種Robbe-Grillet 式的迷.
You know?
你明白麼？
But no real resolution.
但是沒有真正的答案。
- Wow.- [ Chuckles ] It--
-喔。-這個--
Well, I think it's really greatyou're getting it published.
嗯。我覺得你能出版它真是太棒了。
Really. I mean, I know how hard it isjust to write it, even.
真的。我是說，我知道僅僅把它寫出來就很難了。
Yeah.
是啊。
I mean, like me, I've got this paperdue on Friday...
我是說，像我，我的論文星期五就要交了...
and I'm freaked out about it,just like in high school.
我緊張的一塌糊塗，像高中生一樣。
- A paper, huh?- Yeah.
-論文，嗯？-對。
I'm going for a master's degreein horticulture.
我正在讀園藝學的碩士學位。
Sorta chipping away on it.
慢慢啃的。
- Horticulture? Really?- Mmm.
-園藝學？真的？-唔。
I didn't even knowthat there was a college here.
我都不知道這附近還有大學。
Well, I commute to San Luis Obispotwice a week.
噢，我跑通勤到San Luis Obispo，兩週一次。
Horticulture? Wow.
園藝學？喔。
So, do you want to workin a winery or something?
那你是想在釀酒園還是什麼地方工作？
Maybe.
可能吧。
Oh.
噢。
Hmm.
嘸。
So, when can I read your book?
那，我什麼時候才能讀你的書？
[ Laughs ]
[笑]
Well, I-- You know, I-- Well, I do happento have a manuscript in my car.
嗯，我--你知道，我正好有手稿在車裡。
Um, it's not proofed or anything...
呃，還沒有校對過...
so it's-- it's full of typos.
所以會有很多書寫錯誤。
- If you don't mind typos--- Oh, no. Who cares?
-如果你不介意書寫錯誤---不介意，誰管呀？
I'm the queen of typos.
我可是錯別字大王。
Okay.
好的。
[ Stephanie Moaning ]
[ Stephanie 呻吟 ]
[Jack Moans ]
[Jack 呻吟 ]
[ Sighs ]
[ 嘆息 ]
[ Stephanie Continues Moaning ]
[ Stephanie 呻吟 ]
Mmm.
嘸。
Ahh.
啊。
You know, can I ask youa personal question, Miles?
能問你個私人問題麼，Miles?
Sure.
當然。
Why are you so into pinot?
你為什麼那麼喜歡皮諾？
- [ Laughing ]- I mean, it's like a thing with you.
我的意思是，就好像你的一個特徵一樣。
Uh... I don't know. I don't know.
呃...我也不知道，我也不知道。
Um... it's a hard grape to grow.
呃...只是一種很難種植的葡萄。
As you know. Right?
你應該知道，對吧？
It's, uh-- It's thin-skinned...
它，呃，它皮很薄...
temperamental, ripens early.
喜怒無常，熟得很早。
It's-- You know, it's not a survivor...
它--你知道，它很難生存...
like cabernet...
不像卡博耐(cabernet)...
which can just grow anywhere...
可以在任何地方生長...
and thrive even when it's neglected.
甚至沒人管也能興旺。
No, pinot needs constant careand attention. You know?
不行，皮諾需要持久的關心和照料。你知道？
And, in fact, it can only grow...
其實，它只能長在...
in these really specific,little tucked-away corners of the world.
那些極特別的地方世界很少的幾個角落。
And-- And only...
只有--只有...
the most patientand nurturing of growers...
最耐心最精心的種植者
can do it, really.
can do it, really.才能種它，真的。
Only somebodywho really takes the time...
只有那些真正願意花時間的人...
to understand pinot's potential...
真正理解皮諾潛力的人...
can then coax itinto its fullest expression.
才能引導它進入全盛階段。
And then? I mean--
然後呢？我是指--
Oh, its flavors, they're justthe most haunting and brilliant...
哦，它的香味兒，是最持久最輝煌的...
and thrilling and subtle and...
最震撼最微妙的...
ancient on the planet.
最古老的，在整個星球上。
No, I mean, you know, cabernetscan be powerful and exalting too...
我是說，你知道，卡博耐也能很強健很顯耀...
but they seem prosaic to me,for some reason, by comparison.
但它們對我來說太平凡了，因為某種原因，相對而言。
- [ Laughing ]- I don't know. I don't know.
我不知道，我不知道。
What about you?
你覺得呢？
What about me?
我覺得什麼？
I don't know.Why are you into wine?
不知道。你為什麼對葡萄酒著迷？
Oh, I-- I think I--
噢，我--我想 我--
- I originally got into wine through my ex-husband.- Ah.
-我最初對酒著迷是因為我的前夫。-啊。
You know, he had this bigsort of show-off cellar.
你知道，他有一個很大的值得炫耀的酒窖。
- You know?- Right.
-明白麼?-對。
- But then I discovered thatI had a really sharp palate.- Mm-hmm.
-然後我發現我的味覺非常敏銳。-嗯哼。
And the more I drank...
我喝的越多...
the more I likedwhat it made me think about.
我就越喜歡它使我產生的思想。
Like what?
比方說？
Like what a fraud he was.
比方說我意識到他是一個騙子。
[ Laughs ]Wow.
喔。
No, I mean, I like to thinkabout the life of wine.
不，我的意思是，我喜歡去思考酒的生命。
Yeah.
嗯。
How it's a living thing.
它是一種怎樣一種有生命的東西。
I like to think about...
我喜歡思考...
what was going on the yearthe grapes were growing...
在葡萄成熟的一年裡會發生什麼...
how the sun was shining...
太陽是怎樣照耀的...
if it rained.
在下雨的時候。
I like to think about...
我喜歡思考...
all the people who tendedand picked the grapes...
那些照顧和採摘葡萄的人們...
and, if it's an old wine,how many of them must be dead by now.
如果是陳年的酒的話，有多少人現在已經不在人世了。
I like how wine continues to evolve.
我喜歡葡萄酒在不停的進化。
Like,if I opened a bottle of wine today...
好比，如果我今天打開一瓶酒的話...
it would taste different than ifI'd opened it on any other day.
它的味道會不同與我在其他日子打開它。
Because a bottle of wineis actually alive...
因為一瓶酒其實是有生命的...
and it's constantly evolvingand gaining complexity.
而且它不停的進化，不停的得到新的元素。
That is, until it peaks...
這樣，直到它的頂峰...
like your '61 .
就像你那瓶61年的酒。
And then it begins its steady...
然後它開始了平穩的...
inevitable decline.
不可避免的衰退。
Hmm.
嗯。
And it tastes so fucking good.
它的口味變的真他媽的好。
But you know, I-- I, uh--
不過你知道，我--我，呃--
I like other wines besides pinot too.
我還喜歡皮諾以外的其他葡萄酒。
I mean, latelyI've been really into Rieslings.
我是說，最近我開始非常喜歡雷斯林（Rieslings）。
You like Rieslings? Rieslings?
你喜歡雷斯林？雷斯林？
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
There's a bathroom in the back?
這後面有洗手間麼？
- Yeah. It's through the kitchen.- I'll be right back.
-有，穿過廚房就是。-我馬上回來。
[ Screen Door Opens, Closes ]
[門打開，關上]
[ Exhales ]God, you are such a fuckin' loser.
上帝，你他媽的衰人。
You make me so fuckin' sick.
你真他媽讓我噁心。
[ Groaning ]Oh, God. Ah, come on.
噢，上帝。啊，來吧。
[ Exhales ]
[喘氣]
[ Sighs ]
[ 嘆息 ]
[ Sniffs ]
[ 吸氣 ]
Hi.
嗨。
- I was just getting some water.- Okay.
-我過來拿點水。-嗯。
- You want some water?- No.
-你要水麼？-不。
Okay. It's getting kind of late.
好了。現在已經很晚了。
I should really go.
我真的得走了。
[ Puts Glass Down ]
[放下窗子]
[ Sighs ]
[嘆氣]
So you know how to get to the Windmill?Two rights and a left.
你知道去「風車」該怎麼走吧？兩個右轉再一個左轉。
- Got it.- Okay.
-知道了。-好的。
I had a nice time tonight, Miles.I really did.
我晚上過的很愉快，Miles.真的。
Good. So did I.
好。我也是。
- Okay. Well, I'll see you around then.- Um--
-那好吧，再會了。-呃--
Did you still want to read my novel?
你還想看我的小說麼？
Oh, yeah. Of course.
噢，是的，當然。
[ Groans ]
[嘀咕]
Yeah.
是的。
- Great.-Just a sec.
-太好了。-等一下。
- Here.- Oh, wow.
-給。-噢，喔。
Well, I hope you like it.
我希望你喜歡。
And feel free to stop reading it any time.I will not be offended.
你什麼時候看不下去了就別看了，我不會生氣的。
Okay.
好。
- Well, good night, Miles.- Good night.
-那，晚安，Miles.-晚安。
[ Car Door Closes ]
[車門關閉]
#[ Cell Phone Chiming ]
[手機鈴響]
[ Groans ]
[嘀咕]
Oh, fuck.
哦，靠。
- [ Rings ]- [ Loud Grunt ]
-[鈴聲]-[咕嚕聲]
[ Rings ]
[鈴聲]
- [ Miles Sighs ]- [ Ringing Continues ]
[嘆氣]
[ Engine Rumbling ]
[引擎響聲]
That fucking chick is unbelievable, dude.Unbelievable!
那個妞真他媽的難以置信，夥計。難以置信！
Whoo! Boy.
喔！
Ohh, she is nasty, Miles.
哦，她可真下流，Miles.
Nasty, nasty, nasty.!
下流，下流，下流！
- Well, I'm glad you got it out of your system.- Yeah, baby.
-嗯，我很高興你終於發洩了。-是啊，哥們。
Congratulations.Mission accomplished.
恭喜你。任務完成了。
[ Engine Rumbling ]
[引擎響聲]
Oh, hi, Miles!
哦，嗨，Miles!
Hi.
嗨！
- [ Toilet Flushing ]- Hey, you didn't invite Stephanieto come with us, did you?
嘿，你不會請了Stephanie和我們一起去吧？
Oh, listen, man. Change of plans.
哦，聽著，夥計，計劃有變了。
Stephanie's off today, so, you know,I'm thinkin' about goin' on a hike.
Stephanie今天不上班，所以，你看，我想和她去爬山。
We were supposed to play golf.
我們本來今天要去打高爾夫的。
You know what? You go, man.You go. In fact, use my clubs.
你覺得怎麼樣？你自己去，夥計。你自己去。事實上，你可以用我的會員卡。
- They're brand-new.They were a gift from Christine's dad.- [ Disgusted Sigh ]
會員卡都是全新的。是Christine她爸送給我的禮物。
Here, I'll pay for it. Right there.
給，我請客。就用這個。
And then later, the three of us,we can go to The Hitching Post.
等晚一些時候，我們三個可以一起去The Hitching Post。
We could sit at one of Maya's tables.
我們可以坐在Maya的餐桌那兒。
She'll bring us some great wine,you know?
她會給我們拿些好酒，知道麼？
- Then the four of us will do something.- No. Count me out.
然後我們四個可以幹點什麼。不，我不要。
Oh, I see.
哦，我明白了。
Didn't go so great last night, huh?What a shocker.
昨天晚上不是很順利，嗯？真是吃驚啊。
You mean getting drunk and callingVictoria didn't put you in the mood?
你是說喝醉了給Victoria打電話並沒有使你進入狀態？
Dumb fuck.
媽的傻瓜。
- Later, man.- Yeah, well, maybe you shouldcheck your messages first.
晚上見，夥計。是的，不過也許你應該先查一下你的短信。
- [ Escalating Tones ]- Oh, boy.
哦，天哪。
Yeah, she's been leavingmessages here too.
是的，她在這裡也留言了。
Yeah. Okay.
嗯。好的。
- You should call her.- I will. I'll see you.
你應該給她打電話。我會的。再見。
- Right now!- Okay. Fuck!
現在就打！好吧。靠！
- What are you, my mom?- Well.
你是誰呀？我媽？隨便。
Would you mind waiting outside?
你不介意到外面等吧？
- That was fun last night.- Yeah. Good food.
昨天晚上過的很好。是啊。吃的東西不錯。
Hey, I-I talked to Maya this morning.She said she had a fun time too.
嘿，我-我早上和Maya談過了。她說她昨天晚上也很開心。
You should call her.
你應該給她打電話。
- Where's Jack?- Uh, had to make a phone call.
Jack在哪兒？呃，他得打個電話。
Oh.
哦。
Miles. Miles.
Miles. Miles.
Hey, man, uh, do you havethat other condom?
嘿，夥計，呃，上次那個安全套你還有沒有了？
In my jacket.
在我外套裡。
What did, uh, Christine say?
Christine怎麼說？
Lucked out. Got voice mail.Everything's cool.
很僥倖。用語音留言了。一切都沒問題。
- Ha, ha.! Here I am.- [ Stephanie ] Hi.!
哈哈，我來了。嗨！
[ Engine Rewing ]
[引擎響]
- Ready?- Yeah.
好了麼？好了。
[ Child Screaming, Chattering ]
[孩子的叫聲]
Cannonball!
重型炮彈！
[ Female Voice, Electronic ]Please dial your password and press pound.
請輸入您的密碼並按井號鍵。
You have no messages at this time.
目前您沒有留言。
To send a message, press 2--
發送消息，請按2--
[ Clears Throat ]
[清喉嚨]
- [ Moaning, Panting ]- Uh--
-啊--
Not now. Not now!
不要現在進來！
- Yeah.- [ Stephanie Grunting ]
好。
Hey, there you are.
嘿，你來了。
- Yup.- Hey, man.
是的。嘿，夥計。
What are you drinking?
你在喝什麼？
Is it any good?
好不好喝？
Can-- Can I get a glass, please?
我能不能，能不能來一杯？
Thanks.
謝謝。
Stephanie took me outto the pinot fields today, Miles.
Stephanie今天帶我去皮諾種植地了，Miles.
God, it was so awesome.
上帝，真是美啊。
I think I'm really starting to geta handle on the whole process.
我覺得我已經對整個過程摸出些門道來了。
The soil to the vine, and the--what do you call it?
從土壤到藤蔓，還有--你們怎麼說的來著--
The selection to the harvest.
從選種到收穫。
Then that thing they do withthe big containers where they mix it?
就是他們用那個很大的容器攪拌葡萄？
It's really neat, the whole thing.
真是太棒了，整個過程。
Then we ate pinot grapesright off the vine.
我們還從葡萄藤上摘了皮諾葡萄吃。
They were a little sour...
有點酸...
but showing excellent potentialfor structure...
不過表現出出色的構造潛力...
down the line, I think.
從頭至尾，我認為。
Stephanie, man.She really knows her shit.
Stephanie，夥計，她可真懂行。
Hmm. Where is Stephanie?
嗯。Stephanie在哪兒？
Uh, she's upstairs cleaning up.
呃，她在樓上清理清理。
What the fuck are you doing?
你他媽的到底在幹嘛？
- What?- With this chick.
什麼？和那個妞。
What?
怎麼了？
Does she know about Saturday?
她知不知道星期六的事？
Well, not exactly.I've been honest with her.
哦，不知道吧。不過我對她是誠實的。
I haven't told her I'm available.
我並沒有告訴她我是單身啊。
She knows this tripis only for a few days.
她知道我們這趟旅行只有幾天。
Besides, I just--
再說，我--
- Besides what?- I'm-- Well, you know--
再說什麼？我--嗯，你知道--
- The wedding.- What?
婚禮。怎麼了？
I-- I've just been doingsome thinking about it.
我正在考慮。
Oh, you've been thinking. And?
哦，你在考慮了。然後呢？
Might have to putthe wedding on hold, is all.
也許我想把婚禮推遲一下，就這樣。
Look, I know thatthat could be tricky...
你看，我知道這個很難...
- for certain people to accept at first.- Yeah.
很難讓人一開始就接受。嗯。
All right?But life is short, Miles.
是吧？不過人生很短，Miles.
I have to be sure I'm doing the right thingbefore taking such a big step.
我必須在做出這樣一個重大決定前確定自己這樣做是正確的。
You know what?That's not just for my sake.
你知道麼？這也不是光光為了我自己。
I'm looking outfor Christine's feelings too.
我也是為Christine的感情著想。
I mean, being with Stephaniehas completely opened my eyes.
我是說，和Stephanie在一起讓我大開眼界。
She's not uptight or controlling.She's just cool.
她不保守，沒有控制欲。她很棒。
I mean, she smells different,she tastes different.
我是說，她聞起來是不一樣的，她嘗起來是不一樣的。
- She fucks different.- Okay.
她操起來也是不一樣的。好吧。
She fucks like an animal.
她操起來像個動物。
I gotta tell you, man.
我得告訴你，夥計。
I went deep last night.
我昨天晚上插的很深。
Deep.
很深。
I thought I'd get a little understandingfrom you, but I'm not gonna get that.
我原以為我可以從你這兒得到些理解，看來我得不到了。
Understanding about what,Jack?
理解什麼，Jack?
- I might be in love with another woman.- [ Laughs ]
我可能愛上另一個女人了。
In love? Really?
愛上？真的？
Twenty-four hours with some wine-pourerchick, and you're fuckin' in love.
和一個倒酒的女人呆24個小時，你就他媽的愛上她了？
Come on! And you're gonnagive up everything?
算了吧！你願意失去一切麼？
Here's what I'm thinkin'.
我是這樣想的。
You and me, we move up here,we buy a vineyard.
你和我，我們搬到這附近，買一片葡萄園。
You design the wine.I'll handle the business side.
你設計葡萄酒，我來處理生意方面。
You get inspired, maybe writeanother novel, one that can sell.
你得到了靈感，沒準兒能寫另一部小說，一本有市場的。
Oh, my God. No, no.
哦，上帝啊。不會吧。
As for me, if an audition comes up,L.A.'s right there, man.
對我來說，如果有試演，洛杉磯就在附近，夥計。
- It's two hours away. Not even.-Jesus Christ. You're crazy.
就兩個小時的路，可能還不到。上帝，你瘋了。
You've gone crazy.
你已經瘋了。
All I know is that I'm an actor.
我只知道我是個演員。
All I have is my instinct.
直覺對我最重要。
You're asking me to go against it.
你現在讓我違背我的直覺.
[ Stephanie ]Hi, guys.!
嗨，你們好。
Hi. Hi.
嗨，嗨。
- We should probably get going.- Yeah.
我們可能該走了。是的。
Where?
去哪兒？
I know where all the drivers go.
我知道開車的人都去哪兒。
Huh? All right. Here comes the tricky part.There you go. Nice.
嗯？好吧。困難的部分來了。來吧。好。
Nice. Okay, it's the bridge.
好。好的，這兒有個橋。
Golden Gate Bridge. There you go.
金門大橋。來吧。
You know, it's a thing-- I mean,I've gotten over it. You know what I mean?
你知道，有件事--我是說，其實我也經不太在乎了。你知道我的意思麼？
- Mm-hmm.- Stephanie's heard this a thousand times...
嗯哼。Stephanie已經聽過上千次了...
but if I'd bought up in Santa Mariawhen I had a chance...
如果我是在聖瑪麗長大的，如果我有機會
I would've made a fortunewhen they put in that, uh--
我可以賺一大筆錢，就是他們在建那個，呃--
- Home Depot.- Home Depot.
- Home Depot家居.- Home Depot家居.
And those stores.And your father knew about it too.
那些商店呀。你爸爸也知道這些。
He's such a fuckin' chickenshit.
他可真他媽是個膽小鬼。
Always was.Just a fuckin'chickenshit.
總是那樣。就是他媽的膽小鬼。
- Just too scared.- [ Coughing ]
什麼都害怕。
- Is this bothering you? You sure?- It's fine. Yeah.
這個惹你煩了麼？有沒有？沒關係，沒關係。
Hey, man. I'm gonna just make surethat Siena and Stephanie get home safe.
嘿，夥計。我得確保Siena 和 Stephanie安全到家。
- Okay.- All right. Maybe we'll hook up with you later.
好的。好。也許我倆可以晚點再會面。
Sure. Whatever. Maybe I'llgo catch a movie or something.
當然。隨便。也許我可以去看個電影什麼的。
- See you later, Miles.- Thanks, Stephanie. See you.
再見，Miles。- 謝謝, Stephanie. 再見.
- Bye, Siena.- Bye.
- 再見, Siena.- 再見.
- Caryl, very nice meeting you.- I loved talking with you.
- Caryl, 很高興認識你.- 我很喜歡和你聊天.
- Thanks.- If you go out later, call me on my cell.
謝謝。如果你要出去，打我手機。
[ High-pitched Voice ]Okay!
好！
- Okay. That's it?- Yeah.
好。是這個麼？是的。
Actually, could I get a, uh--a Barely Legal, please?
還有，請給我拿一期Barely Legal?
Thank you. No, actually--Sorry. The new one.
謝謝。不，是--對不起，要新的一期。
Okay.
好的。
Thanks.
謝謝。
What-- Oh.
什麼--哦。
- Hey, Miles. How's it hanging?- Hey.
嗨，Miles,玩的怎麼樣？嗨。
Oh, you know me. I love it up here.
哦，你瞭解我。我喜歡這裡。
- How 'bout you?- Busy for a Tuesday night.
你怎麼樣？星期二晚上很忙。
We had a busload of old folkson a wine tour.
有一車老年人來葡萄酒之旅。
Usually they're not too rowdy,but tonight something was going on.
平時他們也不是很吵鬧的但今晚有點奇怪。
I don't know. A full moon or something.Anyway, what can I get you?
我也不知道，沒準是滿月的原因。你想要點什麼？
- Highliner.- Glass or bottle?
- Highliner.杯裝的還是瓶裝的？
- Bottle.- You got it.
瓶的。好的。
Say, is, uh, Maya working?
哎，呃，Maya還在工作麼？
Maya? Uh, no, I haven't seen her.
Maya? Uh, 沒有，我沒看見她.
I think she's off tonight.
我想她今晚調休。
- You okay, Miles?- Yeah, I'm good.
你還好吧，Miles?是的，我還好。
[ Chuckles, Snorts ]
[笑聲]
[ Groans ]
[嘀咕聲]
[ Exhales ]
[喘氣]
Ah, crap.
啊，媽的。
- Did you ever get ahold of Maya yesterday?- Nope.
你昨天晚上見到Maya了麼？沒有。
- Hmm?- No.
嗯？沒有。
She really likes you, man.Stephanie'll tell you.
她很喜歡你，夥計。Stephanie會告訴你的.
- Could you just give me a little room? Please?- Yeah.
你能不能給我點地方？好的。
Thank you.
謝謝。
In life, you gotta strikewhile the iron's hot. Iron is hot.
生活中，有時你得趁熱打鐵。趁熱打鐵。
Sage advice,Jack.
明智的建議，Jack.
- Now, remember, sit back on your heels.- Mm-hmm.
現在，記住，腳後跟站穩。嗯哼。
All right?Turn through the abdomen.
好了麼？轉腹部。
Abdomen.
腹部
- [ Grunts ] Oh, for cryin'--- Nice.
哦，給點尖叫--很好。
[Jack ] What about your agent?You hear anything yet?
你的經紀人怎麼樣了？有信兒了麼？
- [ Miles ] Nope.- What do you think's going on?
沒有。你覺得會有什麼事？
- Could be anything.- You been checking your messages?
什麼事都可能。你檢查你的留言了麼？
- Obsessively.- Huh.
不停的查。嗯。
Guess I'll just have to learn to kiss offanother three years of my life.
看來我得接受我又浪費了生命中的三年。
But you haven't heard anything yet...
但是你還沒有得到任何消息呢...
so don't you think your negativity'sa little premature?
你不覺得你的消極論斷還為時過早麼？
Hmm? All right. You know,fuck the New York publishers.
嘸。好的。你知道。操他的紐約出版商。
Publish it yourself, Miles.I'll chip in.
你自己出版，Miles.我入股。
Just get it out there.Get it reviewed.
把它出版了，找人寫評論。
Get it in libraries.Let the public decide.
放在圖書館裡，讓公眾決定。
[ Sighs ]
[嘆氣]
Don't come over the top.
不要打在表面上。
- Stay still.- Shut up.
保持不動。閉嘴。
It's all about stillness.
保持不動最重要。
- Inner quiet.- Shut up. Shut up. Shut up!
內心的平靜。閉嘴，閉嘴，閉嘴！
Jesus Christ, man!What the hell is wrong with you?
上帝呀，你到底哪根筋搭錯了？
Please,just shut up! Fuck!
求求你了，就閉嘴吧！靠！
- God.- What's with the hostility, man?
上帝啊。你這麼沖幹嗎，夥計？
I know you're a little frustratedwith your life right now...
我知道你目前的生活有些挫折...
- but you can choose to be less hostile.- [ Chuckling ]
不過你可以選擇不那麼敵視。
The fucker hit into us.
那個混蛋打到我們這裡來了。
[ Shouting ]Hurry it up, will ya?
[ Shouting ]快點，行不？
Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
哦，哦。
Hey, that's not cool, asshole!
嘿，這樣不好，笨蛋！
[ Clears Throat ]
[清喉嚨]
[Jack ]Nice shot.Jackoffs.
好球。笨蛋們。
- What the hell are you doing?- Oops. Look out.
你到底在幹什麼？哎呀，小心。
Uh? Uh-huh.
嗯？呃-哼。
Oh. Oh, check it out.
哦，哦，看，看。
- This is gonna be fun. This is gonna be fun.- Go to it.
好戲來了，好戲來了。開過去
[ Roaring ]
[轟鳴聲]
Just don't give up on Maya. Cool, smartchicks like that require persistence.
不要放棄Maya. 像她那樣又酷又聰明的女人需要恆心。
I don't wanna talk about it, please.
我不想談這個了，求你了。
All I know is that she's beautiful,a lot of soul.
我只知道她很美，精神豐富。
She's perfect for you.
她對你非常合適。
I'm just not gonna feel good about this weekuntil I know you guys have hooked up.
如果看不見你們兩個在一起我這周不會好過的。
Don't you want to feel that cozy little boxgrip down on your johnson?
你難道不想要那種溫暖的小盒子加緊你的小弟弟的感覺麼？
Hey! Mind keeping it down, buddy?
嘿！往後想想，夥計？
A woman finds out how I live...
當這個女人發現我是怎樣生活的...
that I'm not a published author,that I'm a liar, essentially...
我並不是一個出版作家，我根本就是個騙子...
any interest she hasis gonna evaporate real quick.
她所有的興趣就會很快消失掉。
If you don't have money at my age,you're not even in the game anymore.
如果你到了我這個年齡還沒有錢，就意味著你連遊戲的資格都沒有了。
You're just a pasture animalwaiting for the abattoir.
你只是一個等在abattoir（法語）裡的牲畜。
- Abattoir. What is that?- Slaughterhouse.
- Abattoir. 什麼意思?- 屠宰場.
Abattoir. Huh.But you know what?
Abattoir. 嗯.不過你知道麼？
You are gonna bea published author...
你會成為一個出版作家...
because you're gonna get the good newsthis week about your book.
因為這個星期你就要聽到關於你的書的好消息了。
- I know you are. I can feel it.- #[ Cell Phone Chiming ]
我知道你會的，我可以感覺到。
Huh. Stephanie.
嗯. Stephanie.
Hey, honey. Yeah.
嗨，寶貝兒，是的。
Yeah. Yeah.
是的，是的。
Yeah!
太好了！
- Hey.- [Jack ] Hi.
嗨。嗨。
[ Stephanie Laughing ]
[ Stephanie 笑 ]
Hey, Miles. I heard you stopped bythe restaurant to see me last night.
嗨，Miles,我聽說你昨晚到餐廳去找我了。
Oh, yeah. No. I mean, uh, yeah.
哦，是的。不，我是說，呃，是的。
I stopped by for a drink.I didn't see you.
我去那裡喝了一杯。不過沒看見你。
- I had class.- Oh.
我去上課了。哦。
Well, nice to see you now.
那，很高興現在見到你。
It's good to see you too.
我也很高興見到你。
- [ Miles ] Syrah.- [ All Chattering ]
席拉酒。
[ Miles ] Oldest Syrah grapesin Santa Barbara County.
聖巴巴拉周圍最古老的席拉葡萄。
Did you know that?
你知道麼？
You didn't know that?
你不知道麼？
[ Maya Laughing ]
[ Maya 笑 ]
[ Man ] The pinot noir grapehas been cultivated perhaps...
黑皮諾葡萄最早開始種植可能是
since antiquity in Burgundy.
從古代勃艮第。
And it is precisely this ancient...
正是這種精確的...
and inherited winemakingknowledge...
從遠古繼承的釀酒知識...
that has contributed to its success.
促成了它的成功。
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
[ 模糊的講話聲]
[ Quiet Chattering ]
[ 小聲交談聲 ]
[ Indistinct ]
[ 模糊的講話聲 ]
[ All Laughing ]
[ 大笑 ]
- I was, like, 1 6, 1 7.- Really?
我在那裡數著，16， 17。真的？
Yeah. I'm gonna die!
是啊，快枯燥死了！
- Oh, God. What a drag.- Mom?
哦，天哪，亂七八糟的。媽媽？
- Oh.- Oh, hey. Hi.
哦。哦，嘿，嗨。
- Is it too loud?- [ Coughing ]
是不是太吵了？
Sorry. Oh, UncleJackwill put you back to bed.
對不起。哦，Jack叔叔帶你上床睡覺。
Come here, little sister. Ooh!
過來，小朋友。哦！
We'll be more quiet, okay?
我們會安靜一點的，好不好？
- Good night. I'm sorry.- I'm so sorry.
晚安。抱歉。非常抱歉。
- My favorite, as far as ice cream--- [ Coughing ]
我最喜歡的，冰淇淋是--
- Chunky Monkey.- [ Maya ] Chunky Monkey.!
- Chunky Monkey.- [ Maya ] Chunky Monkey.!
You guys should come bythe restaurant for lunch today.
你們今天應該到我們餐廳吃午飯。
- Great. What's the latest we can get there?- About 2:30.
很好。我們最晚可以什麼時候到？大概2:30。
Did you hear about this Bordeauxtasting dinner down in Santa Barbara...
你有沒有聽說聖巴巴拉有個波爾多酒品嚐大會...
on Saturday night?
在這個週六晚上？
It's kind of pricey,but if you wanted to go, I'd be into it.
有點貴，不過你如果願意去的話，我也去。
Why don't you just stayfor the weekend?
你們為什麼不能過了這個週末再走？
No, we have to get back Fridayfor the rehearsal dinner.
不行，我們必須得星期五回去排演晚餐？
What rehearsal dinner?
為什麼要排演晚餐？
Who's getting married?
有人要結婚了麼？
- Were you ever gonna say anything?- Yes, of course I was.
你是不是根本什麼都不打算說？我當然打算告訴你的。
Just now I could've told yousome story, but I didn't.
就剛才，我本來可以編個故事騙你，但我沒有。
- I told you the truth. Maya!- Don't touch me!
我已經說實話了，Maya!別碰我！
Just take me home.
送我回家。
Do you have any ideawhat he's been saying to her?
你知不知道他對她都說了些什麼？
- He's an actor, so it can't be good.- Only that he loves her.
他是個演員，所以不會是什麼好話。只是說他又多愛她。
How she's the only woman that's everrocked his world, how he adores Siena...
她是唯一一個震撼他世界的女人，他多麼喜歡Siena...
how he wants to move here andget a place with the two of themand commute when he has to.
他多麼想搬到這兒來，買個地方和她倆住一起，他可以跑通勤。
I'm sure he believed every word of it.
我肯定他自己都以為自己說的每個字都是真的呢。
Please believe me.
請相信我。
I was on the vergeof telling you last night, but--
我昨晚差一點就要告訴你真相了，不過--
But you wanted to fuck me first.
不過你想先操我。
Oh, Maya. No.
不，Maya。不是的。
Yeah.
是的
You know, I've just spentthe last three years of my life...
你知道，我剛剛用了3年的時間...
trying to extricate myself froma relationship that was full of deception...
試著從一場充滿欺騙的婚姻裡解脫出來...
and I'm doing just fine.
我剛剛開始感覺好點。
And I haven't been with anybodysince my divorce...
我離婚以後沒有和任何人在一起過...
so this has been a big deal for me,Maya.
這對我是非常重要事，Maya.
Hanging out with you and, uh--and last night.
和你度過的時光，呃--還有昨天晚上。
I really like you, Maya...
我是真的喜歡你，Maya...
and I am notJack.
而且我並不像Jack.
I'm-- I'm--
我是--我是--
[ Sighs ] I'm his freshman year roommatefrom San Diego State.
在聖地亞哥州立時我是他的大一室友。
- [ Door Closes ]- There's my boy!
我的好孩子回來了！
There he is.But who's your daddy?
他回來了。你爸爸是誰呀？
- Who is your daddy? Oh!-Jack, come on.
你爸爸是誰呀？哦！Jack，算了吧。
- Oh, let me love you.- Let go. Oh!
哦，讓我來愛你吧。放開。噢。
- Let me down,Jack.- [ Laughing ]
放下我，Jack.
I am so proud of you.Ah. Mmm. Mmm.
我真替你驕傲。啊，嘸，嘸。
- Well, that's nice.- Okay. All right. Details.
嗯，非常好。好了，好了，告訴我細節。
- I love details.- No.
我喜歡聽細節。不。
- What?-Jesus. It's private.
什麼？上帝，那是隱私。
You better tell me what happened,or I'll tie your dick in a knot.
你最好把經過告訴我不然，我要把你的小弟弟打個結。
Let's just leave it, okay?
我們就走吧，行不行？
- You didn't get any, did you?- [ Sighs ]
你根本就沒幹，是不是？
- You're a homo.- Yeah, right. Yup, I'm a homo.
你是個同性戀。是的，對了。對，我是同性戀。
Yeah. Yeah.
是的，是的。
Just make up whatever you want,and that's what happened.
隨便你亂想的就是經過。
Write out my gay confession,and I'll sign it.
把我的同性戀自白書寫下來，我會在上面簽字的。
Okay? Just stop pushing meall the time.
好不好？不要老是逼我。
You're an infant,Jack.
你是個嬰兒，Jack.
- This is all a big party for you...- Okay.
整個世界對你就是個大派對...好了。
- but not for me.- Come on.
但對我不是。行了。
I'm sorry, man.
對不起，夥計。
Did you have trouble performing?
你是不是假裝的時候有困難？
- Yeah, that's it.- [ Phone Rings ]
是的，就是這個原因。
- Don't answer it.- [ Rings ]
- Don't answer it.- [ Rings ]
Don't answer it.
不要接。
- Jack.- Hello.
- Jack.- 喂。
[ Chuckling ]Yeah.
是的。
Uh-huh. [ Whispers ] It's Christine.
呃-呃。是Christine。
Yeah. Yeah. Uh-huh.
是的，是的。呃-呃。
Hey, let me call you right back.
嘿，我回來馬上給你打電話。
Miles and I are kindain the middle of something.
Miles和我正有事。
Nah, it's nothing serious.Just--He's having one ofhis freak-outs. Yeah.
沒有，沒什麼重要的，就是--他又開始行為反常了。是的。
- # [ Dance: Woman Singing ]- I love you too. I'll call you back.
我也愛你。我等下打給你。
[ Miles ] This whole week has gone sour.It hasn't gone the way it was supposed to.
整個星期已經變味兒了。這不是我們本來想要的。
I just want to go home.
我想在只想回家。
I know what you need.
我知道你的需要。
[Jack ] How 'bout this one?We didn't hit this one.
這個怎麼樣？我們還沒有喝過這裡的呢。
- Frass Canyon. It's a joke.- You ever actually been in there?
- Frass Canyon. 笑話吧.你原來來過這裡？
- I don't have to.- I say we check it out. We're right here.
用不著來這兒。我說我們還是嘗嘗吧，都已經來了。
#[ Acoustic Guitar ]
[吉他聲]
[ Miles ] It tastes like the backof a fucking L.A. school bus.
它的味道就像他媽洛杉磯校車的屁股。
Now, they probably didn't de-stem...
嗯，他們可能沒有去梗...
hoping for some semblanceof concentration.
想假裝酒的濃度很高。
Crushed it up with leaves and mice...
把它和葉子和老鼠一起碾碎...
and then wound up with this rancid tarand turpentine mouthwash bullshit.
再配上腐臭的焦油和松脂漱口水這些爛東西。
Fuckin' Raid.
他媽的騙人。
Tastes pretty good to me.
我覺得味道挺好。
Hmm. Look.They have a reserve pinot.
嗯。對了。他們有一種保留的皮諾。
- Let me use your phone.- What's up?
-我用下你的電話。-怎麼了？
- I can't take it anymore. I gotta call Evelyn.- Okay.
-我不能再等下去了，我要給Evelyn打電話。-好的。
[ Line Ringing ]
[鈴響]
[ Woman ]Evelyn Berman-Silverman's office.
Evelyn Berman-Silverman 的辦公室.
- Hi,Jennifer. It's Miles again.- Oh, hi, Miles.
- 嗨, Jennifer. 還是我， Miles.噢，嗨，Miles.
- Hi.- Let me see if I can get her.
嗨。我看看能不能接通她。
Okay.
好的。
- You're in luck. I'll put you through.- Okay.
你很幸運。我給你接過去。好的。
- Hi, Miles.- Hi, Evelyn.
- 嗨, Miles.- 嗨, Evelyn.
It's your favorite client.[ Chuckles ]
是你最受寵的客戶。
- How's the trip?- Oh, it's good, it's good.
你的旅行怎麼樣？噢，很好，很好。
You know, we're drinkingsome good wines, kicking back.
你知道，我們就喝喝酒放鬆放鬆。
- It's very nice.- Right.
非常好。是的.
So what's happening?There's still no word, huh?
怎麼樣了？還是沒有回音，嗯？
Well, actually, there is word.
嗯，事實上，已經有消息了。
I spoke to Keith Kurtzmanthis morning.
我早上和Keith Kurtzman通過話了。
Right. And?
嗯。怎麼樣？
And... they're passing.
嗯...他們沒有通過。
Conundrum's passing.He said they really liked it.
"迷題"出版社沒有通過，他說他們很喜歡你的小說。
They really wanted to do it, but they justcouldn't figure out how to market it.
他們非常希望能出版它，但是他們不知道怎麼推銷它。
He said it was a really tough call.
他說很難有市場。
Oh. Right.
噢，是的。
- I'm sorry, Miles.- [ Sighs ]
很遺憾，Miles。
So I don't know where that leaves us.
我不知道我們還能怎麼辦。
I'm not sure how much more mileageI can get out of continuing to submit it.
我不知道繼續投稿還有多少意義。
I think it's one of those unfortunate casesin the business right now--
我想這就是目前出版業不景氣的一個不幸的例子吧--
a-a fabulous book with no home.
一本出色的書卻找不到歸宿。
[ Evelyn's Voice ]The whole industry's gotten gutless.
整個出版業都已經沒有勇氣了。
It's not about the qualityof the books anymore.
並不是說你的書不好。
It's only about the marketing.
只是市場的問題。
- Excuse me. Could I geta, uh, pour down here, please?- Sure.
-打攪一下，能不能給我， 呃-倒在這裡？-當然。
There's a, uh, specialon the Syrah by the case.
這一點上席拉酒有點特別。
Hit me again.
再給我倒上。
Thanks.
謝謝。
Excuse me.Could you just pour me a full glass?
對不起，你能不能給我倒滿？
I'll pay for it, okay?
我會付錢的，好不好？
Sir, this is a winery, not a bar.
先生，這裡是釀酒園，不是酒吧。
Oh. Come on.
噢，得了吧。
Just give me a full goddamn pour.
就他媽給我滿上一杯。
Excuse me.
對不起。
Why don't you buy a bottle,then go outside?
你為什麼不買上一瓶，出去喝呢？
- What are you doing?- I told you I need a drink,so I'm going to help myself.
-你要幹什麼？-我給你講了，我要喝一杯，看來我只好自己動手了。
- Okay, pal? What do you think?- Put the glass down.
-哼，哥們，你想怎麼著？-放下杯子。
Let go of the fucking glass, fucker!
放下他媽的杯子，操！
- [ Grunts ]- [ Pourer Groans ]
[咕咚]
- [ Groaning ]- Mmm.
嘸。
- That's that.- Ho, ho, ho, ho, ho. Ho, buddy. Ho, buddy.
就這麼著。噢，哦，哦，哦，夥計，哦，夥計。
- It's okay.- Get him out ofhere.
沒關係。把他帶出去。
- Thanks a lot!- It's okay. His, uh-- His mother just died.
多謝。沒關係。他， 呃--他媽媽剛死了。
So you'll write another one.You've got lots of ideas, right?
你可以再寫一部。你有很多好點子，對吧？
No, I'm finished. I'm not a writer.
沒了，江郎才盡了。我就不是個作家。
I'm a middle school English teacher.
我只是個中學英語老師。
Ah, the world doesn't give a shitwhat I have to say.
啊，整個世界都不會在乎我想說什麼。
I'm unnecessary.[ Chuckles ]
我的存在是沒必要的。
I'm so insignificant,I can't even kill myself.
我是那麼的不重要，連自殺都不行。
Miles, what the hellis that supposed to mean?
Miles, 這到底是什麼意思?
Come on, man. You know.
行了，夥計，你知道。
Hemingway, Sexton, Plath, Woolf.
海明威，塞克斯汀，普拉斯，沃爾夫
You can't kill yourselfbefore you've even been published.
你不能書都沒有出版就自殺
- [ Sighs ]- What about the guy that wroteConfederacy Of Dunces?
那寫《傻瓜同盟》的那個傢伙呢？
He committed suicide before hewas published. Look how famous he is.
他在書出版之前就自殺了。看他現在多出名。
Thanks.
謝謝。
Just don't give up. All right?You're gonna make it.
別放棄，好麼？你一定會成功的。
Half my life is over...
前半生已經過去了...
and I have nothingto show for it, nothing.
我卻沒什麼可展示的，什麼都沒有。
I'm a thumbprinton the window of a skyscraper.
我是摩天大樓窗戶上的一個指印。
I'm a smudge of excrementon a tissue...
我是擦大便手紙上的一粒糞渣...
surging out to seawith a million tons of raw sewage.
和成千上萬的下水道污穢一起奔向大海。
See? Right there.
看到麼?這就是。
Just what you just said?That is beautiful.
就你剛才說的？就很美
"A smudge of excrementsurging out to sea."
"一粒糞渣奔向大海"
- Yeah.- I could never write that.
-是的。-我就永遠也寫不出來。
Neither could I, actually.I think it's Bukowski.
我也不行。其實，那時布考斯基寫的。
[ Horn Honks Twice ]
[喇叭響]
Hey, baby.[ Chuckling ]
嘿，寶貝。
- Look what I got for our favorite girl.- Motherfucker!
-看我給我們的寶貝女兒帶什麼了。-操你媽！
-Jesus Christ!- You fucking lying piece of shit!
-上帝啊！-操你媽屎一樣的騙子！
You're getting married on Saturday?What's with all that shit you said to me?
你週六就結婚了？那你給我說的那些屁話是什麼意思？
- Stephanie, stop!-[Jack ] I can explain.!
- Stephanie, 別打了!- 我要給你解釋!
- [ Sobbing ] You said you loved me!- I do.!
- 你還說你愛我!- 是真的!
- I hope you die!- Stop it, Stephanie!
- 去死吧！- 別打了, Stephanie!
- [Jack Groans ]- [ Crying ]
- [呻吟聲 ]- [ 哭聲 ]
[ Engine Starts ]
[ 摩托啟動 ]
Fuckface! You too!
一幅豬相！你也是！
Me?
我？
- You fucking told Maya, didn't you?- No, I did not.
-你他媽的告訴Maya了，是不是？-沒有，我沒說。
No, I did not.
沒有，我沒說。
It must have been Garyat The Hitching Post.
肯定是The Hitching Post的Gary.
I think we mentioned it to himthe first night.
我想我們第一天晚上就和他提過了。
Oh, did we mention it?You mentioned it, asshole!
哦，是"我們"提的麼？是你提的，傻瓜！
I'm fucking hurting over here.
我這兒真他媽的疼。
Keep it elevated.
頭抬高一點。
[ Elderly Woman ]No, I don't want anything.
不，我什麼都不要。
- [ Answering Machine Beeps ]- Uh, it's Miles.
呃，是我 Miles。
I had to call and, uh, tell you again...
我必須得打電話，呃，再次告訴你...
how much I enjoyedour time together...
和你在一起我有多麼愉快...
and, uh, how sorry I am...
還有，呃，我有多麼難過...
that things turned outthe way they did.
看著事情變成這樣。
I think you're great, Maya.
我覺得你很了不起，Maya。
Uh, I always have from the first timethat you, uh, waited on me.
呃，我一直就這樣認為，從第一次你，呃，在餐廳為我服務。
Uh, and while I'm at it...
呃，既然我要坦白...
uh, I guess maybe youshould know that my book...
呃，我想也許你應該知道我的書...
is not getting published.
並沒有出版。
I thought this one, uh, had a chance,but I was wrong again.
我原以為這次，呃，可以成的，可是我又錯了。
Once again.
又一次錯了。
So you see, uh...
再見，呃...
I'm not really much of a writer.
我其實並不是個作家。
I am not much of anything, really.
我什麼都不是，真的。
I'm gonna have to have an operation,maybe even a couple of'em.
我可能得做手術了，沒準兒得做兩三個。
They're gonna wait for my nose to heal first,then they break it again.
他們要等我的鼻子先癒合了，再把它打開。
Oh, Christ. Good thingyou have a voice-over career.
哦，上帝。幸好你還可以干旁白解說什麼的。
It's gonna fuck that up too.I oughta sue her ass.
我連他媽那種也幹不了了。我應該起訴她這個混蛋。
The only reason I won'tis to protect Christine.
我不起訴的唯一原因就是為了保護Christine。
- That's thoughtful.- Yeah.
-你可真替人著想。-是啊。
How did Stephanie knowit was on Saturday?
Stephanie怎麼會知道是在星期六？
We didn't get into that with Gary.
我們沒有給Gary說這個吧。
Huh. That's-- Yeah, let me think.
呃，可能是-- 呃，讓我想想看。
- You sure you didn't say anything to Maya?- Yes, I'm sure I'm sure.
-你肯定什麼都沒有對Maya說？-是的，我保證，我保證。
And just what are you implying,Jack?
你會讓人怎麼想，Jack?
I'm really pissed off at you about all this,if you want to know the truth.
我對你所作的一切非常生氣，如果你想知道我的真實想法的話。
What is Maya going to think of me now,just for associating with you?
Maya現在會對我怎麼看，就因為我和你關係這麼好？
I don't know. Sure seems fishy.
我不知道，肯定她覺得你很可疑。
Well.
是的。
[ TV:Man ] Wherever there's a fightso hungry people can eat...
[TV:每當人們為飢餓的人作戰...]
I'll be there.
[我會在那裡]
Wherever there's a copbeating up a guy...
[每當警察實施暴力...]
I'll be in the way guys yellwhen they're mad.
[我會在瘋狂尖叫的人們中]
What's this look like to you?
你覺得看起來像什麼？
Uh, it looks like you werein a bad car accident.
呃，我覺得像發生了嚴重的車禍。
[ TVContinues ] When the peopleare eating the stuff they raised--
[TV:當人們吃著自己種養的--]
I'm hungry.
我餓了。
- [ People Chattering ]- [ Woman ] Here we go.
來了。
- Nice.- Thank you.
-很好。-謝謝。
- And here is your Handi Wipes.- Oh.
-這是你的小餐巾。-哦。
So that's what those are. For a minuteI thought you were promoting safe sex.
噢這是小餐巾啊，我差點以為你們在宣傳性安全。
That's a good one.I'll have to remember that one.
這個笑話好。我要記住這個笑話。
- I'll be right back with your corn bread.- All righty.
-我馬上就給你拿玉米麵包來。-好的。
Bet you that chick's two tons of fun.
我保證那個妞非常非常好玩。
- You know, the grateful type?- Mm-mmm.
-你知道，很舒適的那種？-嘸。
I don't know.I wouldn't know about that.
我不知道。我也不想知道。
Mmm.
嘸。
- Hmm.- Here you go.
-嘸。-來了。
Nice technique there... Cammi.
技術很好...Cammi
Thank you. All in the wrist.[ Giggles ]
謝謝，都是手腕功夫。
You know,you look really familiar to me.
你知道，你看起來很眼熟
- Are you from around here?- Actually, we're from San Diego. Why?
-你住在這附近麼？-其實我們是從聖地亞哥來的。怎麼了？
I don't know.You just seemed really familiar to me.
我不知道。我就是看著你眼熟
- Never mind. Enjoy your meal.- Hang on. Hang on.
-別介意，用餐吧。-等一下，等一下。
Um, did you ever knowa Derek Sommersby?
呃，你知不知道Derek Sommersby?
Dr. Derek Sommersbyfrom One Life To Live?
《一次人生》電視劇裡的Derek Sommersby博士？
Just have to imagine himwith a bandage and shorter hair.
你想像一下他貼著邦迪，剪著短髮。
No way!
不會吧！
No way! Oh, my gosh!
不會吧！哦，上帝！
[ Squealing ]That's great.! Oh, my goodness.!
太好了！哦，上帝啊！
Could you tell me wherethe bathroom is, please?
你能告訴我洗手間在哪裡麼？
Oh, yeah. It's right over there,right past the buffalo. Wow!
噢，就在那。過了那個野牛就是。喔！
Oh, my gosh. I can't believeyou're sitting at my table.
噢，上帝啊。我簡直不敢相信你坐在我的餐桌。
Listen, man, Cammi gets offin an hour, so I was thinking...
聽著，夥計，Cammi一個小時後下班，所以我想...
I'd just hang around, have a drink.
在這兒多點一會兒，喝點酒。
- You know, make sure she gets home safe.- [ Laughs ]
你知道，送她安全回家。
You're joking, right?
你在開玩笑吧，是不是？
No.
不是。
Un-fucking-believable.
真他媽不敢相信。
Can't we just go back to the moteland hang out...
我們能不能就回旅館呆著...
get up early,play nine holes of golf...
早上早點起，打打高爾夫...
before we head home?
回家之前就這樣？
Listen, man, you're my friend...
聽著，夥計，你是我的朋友...
and I know you care about me.
我知道你關心我。
I know you disapprove,and I respect that.
我知道你反對。我尊重這些。
But there are some things that I have to dothat you don't understand.
但有些事我必須得做，你並不理解。
You understand literature,movies, wine...
你瞭解文學，電影，葡萄酒...
but you don't understand my plight.
但你並不瞭解我的困境。
- [ Pounding On Door ]- [ Miles Groans ]
- [ 敲門聲 ]- [ 嘀咕 ]
[ Pounding Continues ]
[ 敲門聲 ]
Yeah?[ Sighs ]
來了。
- Holy shit!Jesus Christ!- Fuck. Fuck.
-天哪！上帝！-靠，靠。
God, it's fucking freezing out there!
上帝，我他媽的在哪兒快凍僵了。
- God, yeah.- Vicodin. Where's the Vicodin?
- 天哪，是。- Vicodin呢. 哪兒有 Vicodin?
Uh--
呃--
Oh.[ Panting ]
噢。
Here.
給。
Oh. Oh.
噢，哦。
Fucking chick's married, man.
操他媽的那個妞已經結婚了。
What?
什麼？
Her husband works the night shift, and hecomes home and catches me on the floor...
她老公上夜班，他回家在地板上抓住我們...
with my cock in his wife's ass.
我的小弟弟在她老婆屁股裡。
Oh,Jesus Christ.Jesus.Jack!
噢，上帝，上帝。 Jack!
- And you walked all the way from Solvang?- No, ran.
-你一路從Solvang走回來的？-不是，是跑回來的。
Twisted my ankle too.
腳腕也扭了。
- That's five klicks,Jack.- Fuckin'-A right, it's five klicks.
-那可有5公里啊，Jack.-他媽的，對，有5公里。
At one point I had to cutthrough an ostrich farm.
有一段我還得穿過一個鴕鳥牧場。
- Those fuckers are mean.- [ Giggling ]
那些鴕鳥夠狠。
[ Laughing, Sighs ]
[ 笑 ]
[ Hysterical Giggling ]
[ 狂笑 ]
Whoo!
嗚！
- Oh.! [ Laughing ]- We gotta go back.
- 哦。- 我們還得回去。
[ Chuckles ]What?
什麼？
We gotta go back. I left my wallet.
我們得回去。我把錢包落在那裡了。
Credit cards, cash, my fucking I.D.
信用卡，現金，他媽的身份證。
- Everything. We gotta go back.- Big deal. It's fine.
- 所有的東西。我們得回去。- 很嚴重。沒關係。
Don't worry about it. We'll call nowand we'll cancel your cards.
別擔心。我們現在就打電話把你的卡都取消。
No, Miles,you don't understand.The wedding rings.
不行，Miles，你不明白。我的結婚戒指。
The wedding rings are in my wallet.
結婚戒指在我的錢包裡。
Fine, they're in your wallet, and youleft your wallet in some bar, okay?
沒關係，在你錢包裡。你把錢包丟在某個酒吧裡了，行不行？
- Christine will understand.- She had to order them special.
- Christine 會理解的.- 她特別定制的兩個戒指。
It took her forever to find 'em.
她花了很長很長時間才挑到的。
They've got this design of dolphinsand our names engraved in Sanskrit.
那上面有海豚的設計，有梵語刻的名字。
We gotta go back, man.Christine will fucking crucify me, Miles.
我們得回去，兄弟。Christine 會把我釘死在十字架上, Miles.
No way, no way, no way.
不可能，不可能，不可能。
Please. Please!
求求你了，求求你了！
Forget it.Your wallet was stolen in some bar.
算了吧。你的錢包在酒吧被偷了。
- It happens every day.- No, we gotta go back and get my wallet, Miles.
我跟你說，那兩個戒指是不可取代的。
I'm telling you,those rings are irreplaceable.
-這種事情每天都有。-不行，我們必須得回去把錢包拿回來，Miles.
Look, I know I fucked up, okay?I know I fucked up.
看，我知道我自己有多糟，好麼？我知道把事情搞砸了。
- But you've gotta help me.- Yeah.
-但你得幫幫我。-是的。
You've gotta help me, Miles,please.! Please.!
你必須得幫我，Miles.求你了，求你了！
I can't lose Christine, Miles.
我不能失去Christine, Miles.
I just-- I can't.I can't lose Christine.
我真的--不能。我不能失去Christine。
- Mm-hmm.- I know I fucked up.
- 嘸嘸。- 我知道我搞砸了。
I know I did a bad thing, all right?And I know I'm a bad person.
我知道我干了壞事，行不行？我知道我是個壞蛋
I know I am. But you gotta help me!You have to help me, Miles.
我知道我是。但是你得幫我。你必須得幫我，Miles.
Okay? Tell me you'll help me.
好不好？告訴我你會幫我的。
If I lose Christine, I-I-I--
如果我失去了Christine，我-我--
I'm nothing.
我什麼都不是了
I just have-- I'm nothing.
我真的-我什麼都不是了。
[ Sobbing ]God.
天哪。
- [ Miles ] Did she tell you she was married?- Yeah.
-她有沒有告訴你她結婚了？-說了。
So what the fuck were you thinking?
那你她媽的是怎麼想的？
Wasn't supposed to be back till 6:00.Fucker rolls in at 5:00.
他本來說是6：00回來的。結果5：00就滾回來了。
[ Miles ]Cutting it a little close, don't you think?
卡時間卡得有點緊，你不覺得麼？
- This is the block.- You sure?
-就是這片。-你確定？
Yeah.
是的。
That's it. That's it.
就是這個，就是這個。
That's the one right there.
絕對是這個。
- Yeah?- Yeah.
-是麼？-是的
Okay.
好的。
All right.Okay, so what's the plan?
好了。那，你打算怎麼辦？
Uh, the plan is...
呃，我打算...
you go.
你去。
- Me?- 'Cause of my ankle.
-我？-因為我的腳腕。
Still hurts.Just go explainthe situation, Miles.
還很疼。你去解釋一下情況，Miles。
[ Laughs ]Explain the situation. Yes.
解釋情況。是麼。
"Excuse me, sir. My friend was the oneballing your wife a couple of hours ago.
"對不起，先生。我的朋友就是兩個小時前操你老婆的那個
"Really sorry. He seems tohave left his wallet behind.
"很抱歉。他好像把錢包落在這兒了
I was wondering if I could come inand just poke around. I don't know."
"我想我能不能進去四處找找，我不知道。"
- Yeah,just like that. That's good.- Oh, for Christ's sake.
- 對，就像那樣，挺不錯的。- 哦，看在上帝的份兒上。
Oh, fuck it! I'll go.I guess I have to do everything.
哦，去他媽的！我去。什麼事都得我做。
No. Hold on.
別。等一下。
#[ Stereo:Man Singing Rock, Faint ]
[搖滾樂]
[ Cammi Whimpers ]
[ Cammi 呻吟聲 ]
[ Whimpers ]
[ 呻吟聲 ]
[ Cammi Shouts ]
[ Cammi 叫聲 ]
[ Squeals ]
[ 尖叫 ]
[ Laughs ]
[ 笑 ]
[ Man ] You think I don't fuck you, bitch?I'm fucking you now.
你以為我不會操你麼，婊子？我現在就操你
I'm a bad girl. I'm a bad girl.!
我是個壞女人。我是個壞女人。
You picked him up and you fucked him,didn't you, bitch?
你把他撿回來操他，是不是，婊子？
Yeah, I picked him up and I fucked him.I'm a bad girl.!
是的，我把他撿回來操他。我是個壞女人。
You liked fucking him,didn't you, you little whore?
你喜歡操他，是不是，你這個妓女？
I liked it when you caught me fucking him!Oh, yes! Oh, yeah!
我就喜歡你抓住我操他！Oh, yes! Oh, yeah!
You are a bad bitch.
你這個臭婊子。
- Yeah, you caught me.- You're such a whore.
- 對，你抓住我。- 你這個妓女。
Oh,yeah.!
哦，對！
- Oh, baby.- Oh, it's so good.!
- 哦，baby.- 哦，真好！
[ Groaning, Grunting ]
[呻吟]
[ Cammi ]I fucked him.
我操了他。
- [ Man ] You're so bad.- I am. Yeah.
- 你夠壞。- 是的，是的。
[ Groaning ]You are such a whore.
你這個妓女。
- What the fuck.!- The wallet.! He's got Derek's wallet.!
- 他媽的怎麼了？- 錢包！他把Derek的錢包拿走了！
[ Radio:Man ] I think theywere surprised by the level of protest...
[收音機：我想他們對抗議的嚴重程度感到震驚]
that was really happeningwithin the company.
[這些事情居然真的在公司發生了]
The injustice may be their plan,and they said, "Well, we can'tjust go--"
[他們要討回公道，他們說我們不能就這樣算了--]
- Oh! Here's your wallet! Oh, shit!- Motherfucker!
- 哦，給你的錢包！哦，媽的！- 操你媽的！
- [ Grunting ]- Open the goddamn door!
他媽的開門。
- I'm gonna kill your ass.!- You got it.! You got my wallet.!
- 我要殺了你，傻瓜！- 你拿到了！你拿到我的錢包了！
I'll find you! I will find you, bub!I'll find your ass!
我會找到你的！我會找到你的，小傢伙！我會找到你這個傻瓜的!
You're mine, man! You're mine!
你逃不了的，你逃不了!
Fuck you.! I'm gonna get your ass.!
操你媽的！我會抓住你的！
- You wanna let me drive?- No, it's all right. I got it.
- 你想讓我開麼？- 不用，這樣很好。我來開。
Hey, you know, you oughtainvite Maya to the wedding.
嘿，你知道，你應該請Maya一起去婚禮。
Hmm.
嘸。
Somehow I thinkinviting Maya to the wedding...
我覺得請Maya去婚禮...
is not the right moveat this juncture.
在這個節骨眼上不合適
I don't know.
我不知道。
In fact,after all of your shenanigans...
其實，在你那些騙劇之後...
it's gonna be hard for meto ever go to The Hitching Post again.
我覺得再去The Hitching Post都困難。
You know, there was a nice wayto respond to that.
你知道，應該有個好點的方式回答我。
- Come on. Let me drive.- No, I got it. You should rest.
- 來吧，讓我來開。- 不，我來開。你應該休息。
You know what? I feel like driving.
你猜怎麼著？我很想開。
Okay.
好吧。
Uh... hey, put on your seat belt, okay?
呃...嘿，把安全帶繫好，好麼？
I was just about to.What's the problem?
我正要系呢。有什麼問題麼？
-Just want to remind you to be safe.- We missed the entrance.
- 只想提醒你注意安全。- 我們錯過入口了。
What are you doing,Jack?Hey, hey, hey, hey!
你要幹什麼，Jack?嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿！
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! What the hell are you doing?- Hang on.
- 喔，喔，你到底要幹什麼？- 等一下.
Jack!
Jack!
What the fuck!
他媽的怎麼搞得？
- You said it looked like an accident.- What the fuck!
- 你說的看起來像出了交通事故。- 他媽的！
I'll pay for it.
我會出錢的.
Jesus. Christ,Jack!Oh, for Ch-- Look at this!
上帝啊,Jack!哦，你看看這兒!
- Huh.- Oh.
- 嗯。- 哦。
I don't know.
不知道。
Doesn't look like anyonewas injured in this one.
好像這樣車裡的人不會受傷。
No. No.
不會吧，不。
- Watch your head.- Yeah.
- 注意你的頭。- 好的。
Boy, you broke a couple of'em,you know.
天哪，你弄斷了好幾處，你知道麼。
- Whatever. Sorry.- No, no, no. It's not "whatever."
- 隨便，對不起。-不行，不行，不行。這個不能"隨便"。
You fuckin' derelict.
你他媽的廢物。
You ready?
準備好了麼？
Just get it over with.
一不做二不休。
[ Engine Revving ]
[ 引擎響]
Okeydoke. All right.
好了，好了。
Well, I guess that's about it.
嗯，我想就這樣了。
- Want to come inside?- Uh, no. No, you're on your own.
- 想進去麼？- 哦，不了。不了，全靠你自己了。
All right. I guessI'll see you at the rehearsal.
好吧。我想晚餐預演的時候再見。
Yup.
是的。
- [ Laughing ]- I love you, man.
我愛你，兄弟。
Yeah. Back at ya.
是的。我也愛你。
- Miles, don't drive away until they see the car.- I know, I know, I know.
- Miles, 等他們看到你的車再開走。- 我知道，我知道，我知道。
Hey, wait a second. Wait a second.How come I wasn't hurt?
嘿，等一下，等一下。為什麼我沒有受傷？
'Cause you were wearing your seat belt.
因為你系安全帶了。
Nicely done.
沒破綻了。
[ Car Door Closes ]
[車門關閉]
[ Engine Starts ]
[ 引擎發動 ]
- Hi.-Jack.
- 嗨。-Jack.
- Yeah.- Uh, Christine, Mike!
- 是的。- 呃, Christine, Mike!
[ Priest Speaking Armenian ]
[牧師講亞美尼亞語]
Amen.
阿門。
#[ Organ ]
[風琴聲]
#[ Woman Singing In Armenian ]
#[ 亞美尼亞語歌聲 ]
Hey, Miles.
嘿, Miles.
Hi, Vicki.Wow, you look beautiful.
嗨, Vicki.喔，你真美。
Thanks.
謝謝。
Um, this is Ken Cortland,my husband.
嗯，這是 Ken Cortland,我丈夫.
- How are you?- How are you?
-你好。-你好。
- Good, thanks.- Yeah, yeah. Nice to meet you.
-很好，謝謝。-是的，是的。很高興見到你。
- You're a lucky guy.- Yes, I am. Thank you.
-你很幸運。-是的，我是的。謝謝。
Yeah.
嗯。
Well, I'll just wait for you at the car.
那，我在車裡等你了。
- It was great meeting you, Miles.- Ken.
- 很高興見到你，Miles.- Ken.
- Well, that was big of him.- Yeah, he's good that way.
- 嗯，他可真大度。- 是啊，他這方面很好。
- He's very considerate.- That's great.
- 他很替人著想。- 那很好。
So how are you doing?
你怎麼樣了？
Since the last time we spoke?I don't know.
可能好些了，也可能更糟了。
- So what's happening with your book?- Um, universally rejected.
- 那你的書怎麼樣了？- 嘸，很不幸被拒了。
- Strike three.- Oh, Miles, that's awful.
- 事不過三。- 哦，Miles，太糟糕了。
What are you gonna do?
你打算怎麼辦？
Back to the drawing board,I guess. Or not.
回到講台上，我想，或者不。
I don't know.
我不知道。
So, anyway, you're married.
嗯，不管怎樣，你結婚了。
Congratulations. You look happy.
恭喜，你看上去很幸福。
- I am.- Good.
- 我是幸福的。- 很好。
Seems like everybody's getting married.
看起來每個人都結婚了。
Last year was all divorces.This year it's all weddings.
去年都是離婚的。今年都是結婚的。
- Cyclical, I guess.- I guess.
- 週期性的，我想。- 是的。
Well, uh, what do you saywe hit the reception?
嗯，我們一起參加招待會怎麼樣？
Have some champagne,toast the newlyweds, huh?
喝點香檳，給新人們祝詞，嗯？
Not me. I'm not drinking.
我不行，我不喝酒了。
You quit drinking. Really?
你誡酒了，真的？
I'm pregnant.
我懷孕了。
I see.
明白了。
Yes, I see. Great.
嗯，明白了，很好。
Well, congratulations again, Vicki.
那，再次恭喜你，Vicki。
Boy, that's wonderful news.
天哪，這可是個好消息。
- See you over there, Miles?- Yeah.
- 那邊見, Miles?- 好的.
[ Car Door Closes ]
[ 車門關閉]
Hmm.
嗯.
[ Boy ] "'The marrow ofhis bone, 'I repeated aimlessly.
"他的骨髓，"我漫無目的的重複著。
"This, at last, penetrated my mind.
這，至少，穿透了我的心靈。
"Phineas had diedfrom the marrow of his bone...
Phineas已經死了，從他的骨髓中
"flowing down his bloodstreamto his heart.
鮮血流向他的心臟。
"I did not cry then or ever about Finny.
我並沒有哭，也沒有為Finny哭。
"I did not cry even when I stood...
我甚至在葬禮上都沒有哭，站在那裡...
"watching him being lowered intohis family's straitlaced burial ground...
看著他被放進他家波士頓外...
"outside of Boston.
刻板的家庭墓地裡。
"I could not escape the feelingthat this was my own funeral...
我無法逃脫這種感覺，好像這是我自己的葬禮...
and you do not cry in that case. "
而你是不會在自己的葬禮上哭的。
Should I keep readingthe next chapter, Mr. Raymond?
我要不要繼續讀下一章？Raymond先生？
Uh, no, no.We'll pick up there Monday.
呃，不用，不用。我們下週一再繼續。
[ Beep ]
[滴]
[ Male Voice, Electronic ]One new message.
您有一條留言。
[ Maya ]Hello, Miles. It's Maya.
你好, Miles. 是 Maya.
Thanks for your letter.
謝謝你的信。
I-I would have called sooner...
我-我應該早點打電話...
but I think I needed some time to thinkabout everything that happened...
但我需要些時間想一想已經發生的一切...
and what you wrote to me.
還有你寫給我的東西。
Another reason, um,I didn't call you sooner...
還有一個原因，呃，我沒有早點打...
is because I wanted to finish your book,which I finally did last night.
是因為我想讀完你的小說，我昨晚終於讀完了。
And I think it's really lovely, Miles.
我真的認為很棒，Miles。
You're so good with words.
你用詞很嫻熟。
Who caresif it's not getting published?
誰在乎到底有沒有被出版啊？
There are so many beautifuland... painful things about it.
裡面有很多很美...很傷感的東西。
Did you really go through all that?
你真的都經歷過麼？
Must have been awful.
一定很痛苦。
And the sister character--geez, what a wreck.
還有姐姐那個人物--天哪，真是落魄。
But I have to say that, well,I was really confused by the ending.
但是我得說，嗯，結尾讓人很迷惑。
I mean, did the fatherfinally commit suicide, or what?
我的意思是，那個父親到底是自殺了還是怎麼回事？
It's driving me crazy.
都讓我想瘋了。
Anyway...
反正...
it's turned cold and rainy here lately...
這裡最近變冷了，經常下雨...
but I like winter.
但是我喜歡冬天。
So, listen, if you ever do decide to comeup here again,you should let me know.
嗯，聽著，如果你還想過來的話，你應該告訴我一聲。
I would say stop by the restaurant,but to tell you the truth...
我是說去我們餐廳，不過說實話...
I'm not sure how much longerI'm gonna be working there...
我也不知道我還會在那裡工作多久...
because I'm going to graduate soon.
因為我快畢業了.
So I'll probably want to relocate.
所以可能我會換個地方.
I mean, we'll see.
我是說，再看吧。.
Anyway, like I said,I really loved your novel.
反正，就像我說的，我真的很喜歡的你的小說.
Don't give up, Miles.Keep writing.
別放棄，Miles.繼續寫下去。
I hope you're well.
希望你一切都好。
Bye.
再見。